字幕制作: 呆呆@CMCT
1930年代经济大萧条与法西斯崛起
数以千计的美国人加入美国共产党
二战时美国与苏联同盟后
更多人加入了美国共产党
编剧家达尔顿·特朗勃长期倡议劳工权益
也在1943年成为共产党员
但冷战却使美国共产党员们饱受质疑
1947年 洛杉矶北部
奥斯卡最佳改编剧本提名《女人万岁》
《强尼上战场》原著 达尔顿·特朗勃
《比翼鸟》
编剧 达尔顿·特朗勃
《温柔的伙伴》主演 金杰·罗杰斯
没人想死得早 死得穷 死得孤独
你想要什么 洛可？
What do you want, Rocco?
人们希望的
What we all want.
只是不想死得早 死得穷 死得孤独
To not die young, poor or alone.
曼尼
Manny...
那些家伙…
These guys, they...
如果我不交出他们想要的东西
I don't give them what they're after,
他们会杀了我
they'll kill me.
别动 洛可
Hold it, Rocco.
如果我们不跟那些家伙作对
We don't fight these guys.
或许你能…
Sure, maybe you get that...
- 烦 讨厌 - 卡
- Shit. God damn it. - Cut!
抱歉 各位
Sorry, everyone.
我们再来一次 艾迪 我不知道发生了什么
We're going again, Eddie. I don't know what happened.
对不起 山姆
Sorry, Sam.
偏偏在编剧来的时候出糗
Of course, the one day the author is among us.
虽然他来了 但我们跟他不是一伙的
Among us. Sure as hell ain't one of us.
我的精彩台词是什么 特朗勃？
What's my brilliant line, Trumbo?
我正好拿在手上
Oh! I've got it right here.
"或许你能如愿活得长长久久"
"sure, maybe you get that long, happy life we all want."
那你要我对抗什么？
So, what do you got me fighting for then?
大家和平共处 友善待人嘛
Well, peace on Earth. Good will toward men.
没这回事 这里可是美国
Well, you can't do that. This is America.
好吧 那性爱和金钱呢？
All right. How about sex and money?
这才像话 二件大家最爱的事物
There you go. Two things we all love.
是
Well...
每个美国公民的小小信仰
One of your little sermons on citizenship.
好 重拍一次
All right, going again.
米高梅找来了黄金阵容
Mayer lined up the A Team.
山姆·伍德 导演 达尔顿·特朗勃 重写剧本
Sam Wood to shoot, Dalton Trumbo for rewrites.
罢工使一切停摆
I had no crew, I couldn't work.
老天有眼
So, good, fingers crossed
根本不该让你工作
You wouldn't work.
你跨越警戒线去布景工人罢工阵营
God forbid you cross a picket line for set builders.
他们到底关剧本什么事？
What the hell do set builders have to do with writing?
剧本中的场景由他们搭建
What writers write, builders build.
而他们搭的场景由你拍摄
What they build, you shoot.
你靠拍片赚进大把银子
Now, you make all the money you possibly can.
为何他们不能？为何我们不能帮他们？
So do I. Why shouldn't they? And why can't we help them?
你家有游泳池 还好意思谈共产主义
Listen to you, the swimming pool Soviet.
拜托 你赢了
Oh, for God's sakes, you won!
山姆 罢工结束了
Sam, the strike is over.
你只是想当一个仁慈的胜利者
And you just might try being a gracious winner!
你们这些人真是没完没了
You know, it's never over with you people!
罢工接二连三
Strike after strike after strike!
"你们这些人"？
"You people"?
我们不顾一切只为追求正义
Whatever it takes to seek justice!
好吧 你都知道什么？
Hey, you know what?
我们都 一笑而过
We've all... Laugh it up.
- 我们为何不休息他六个月？- 别 山姆
- Why don't we all take six months off? - Oh, come on, Sam!
- 那我也要来罢工 - 恭喜你
- I'm gonna go on strike... - Good for you.
抗议那些罢工的人
against people who go on strike.
山姆 山姆
Sam, Sam...
这次我绝不会越线过去你的阵营
And I won't cross your picket line either.
我受够了 特朗勃
Oh, give me that, Trumbo! You're just...
你知道什么？
You know what? You know what?
我已经浪费够多时间…
I've spent a hell of a long time... What?
你这不是在帮忙 艾迪
You're not helping... Eddie...
山姆 我们得讨论明天要拍的戏
Sam, Sam. We gotta talk about those scenes tomorrow.
真是一场灾难 是谁写的烂戏？
Disaster. Who the hell wrote that crap?
不过 首先
But, uh, first...
我可以请你跳一支舞吗？
May I have this dance?
艾迪 你把我的酒弄洒了
Eddie... You're spilling my drink.
好玩吗？
Having fun?
永远都这么好玩
Eternally.
霍珀小姐
Miss Hopper.
欢迎收看《好莱坞日讯》
Dateline, Hollywood.
顶尖专栏作家赫达霍珀的办公室
The offices of top columnist Hedda Hopper.
我从电影之都向大家捎来祝福
Greetings from our film capital,
这里阳光普照 充满乐趣
where all is sun and fun.
是吗？众多名人聚集于此
Or is it? You see the famous faces here?
丹尼凯 亨佛莱鲍嘉
Danny Kaye, Humphrey Bogart,
以及他美丽的新娘 洛琳·白考儿
his dishy bride Lauren Bacall.
他们都宣称与罢工的剧组人员站在一起
All of whom have declared solidarity with film crews
要求提高工资
picketing for higher wages
联合罢工迅速转为暴力抗争
in walkouts that quickly turned violent.
实则由危险的激进份子策动
Because these strikes were, in fact,
the work of dangerous radicals.
这是《双重保险》中的艾迪华·罗宾森
Here, we see actor Edward G. Robinson,
star of Double Indemnity.
这是达尔顿·特朗勃
And this is writer Dalton Trumbo,
和很多参加并支持罢工的人一样
who is, like many of those strikers and their supporters,
他也是共产党员
a registered communist.
联合罢工的幕后黑手是谁？
Who exactly is behind these walkouts?
你们创造了电影
You actually create something...
这样公平吗？
Now, is that fair?
不公平 不公平
No! No!
我们的民选众议员
Our elected leaders will find out.
约翰·帕奈尔·汤马斯
Congressman J. Parnell Thomas
将率领非美活动调查委员会找出答案
and his House Un-American Activities Committee.
共产主义不是远在天边的威胁
Communism is not some faraway threat.
最危险的共产分子就在美国
It's most dangerous agents are here,
掌握了广播与银幕
controlling the airwaves and movie screens.
控制了旗下的员工与工会
Taking over its employees and their unions.
我们必须认清 他们就是敌人
They need to be identified as the enemies they are.
共产分子的目标是统治世界
NARRATOR: Communists, their goal:
world domination.
他们发起新型战争
The frontline of a new kind of war.
冷战
A cold war.
企图败坏民主价值
A conspiracy to corrupt democratic values
并推翻这个国家
and bring about the overthrow of this nation.
梅兹睡着了
Mitzi fell asleep.
你就是新闻里的那个人？
Hey! That you in the news reel?
是我没错
Yes, it was.
叛徒
Traitor.
天啊 亲爱的
Oh, my God! Honey.
没事 我没事 这伤不到我
No, I'm all right, I'm all right. No harm done.
真的？
Are you sure? Oh.
来吧 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
爸
Dad?
你是共产党员吗？
Are you a communist?
我是
I am.
这样犯法吗？
Is that against the law?
没有
It is not.
那个戴宽帽的女士说 你是危险的激进分子
The lady with the big hat said you were a dangerous radical.
是吗？
Are you?
激进分子？或许吧
Radical? Maybe.
只有那些泼可乐的人才会觉得我危险
Dangerous. Only to men who fling Cokes.
我热爱国家
I love our country.
我们有一个好政府
And it's a good government.
但还可以好上加好 你不觉得吗？
But anything good could be better, don't you think?
妈是共产党员吗？
Is Mom a communist?
不是
No.
那我呢？
Am I?
那么 我们来做个正规测验吧
Well, why don't we give you the official test?
有一天 妈妈做了你最爱的午餐
Mom makes your favorite lunch.
火腿起司三明治
Ham and cheese.
到了学校 你发现有人没午餐吃
And at school, you see someone with no lunch at all.
你会怎么办？
What do you do?
分享
Share.
分享？
Share?
你不会叫他们去找工作？
Well, you don't tell them to just go get a job?
不会
No.
你不会给他们提供利率6%的贷款？这很明智的
Oh. You offer them a loan at 6%. Oh, that's very clever.
爸
Dad.
那你是不把他们放在眼里？
Ah, then you just ignore them.
我不会
No.
那么…
Well, well.
你就是个小共产分子
You little commie.
特朗勃 你讲的话总是只有自己听得懂
Trumbo, as usual, you only make sense to you.
你是共产党员 我是民主党员
Now, let them call you a communist, me a Democrat.
这二个都是合法政党
They're both legitimate parties.
你们虽然又贱又烂 但并不违法
Yours is just meaner and duller, but there's nothing illegal about any of it.
- 你等着瞧 - 汉特
- Yet... - Hunter.
叫你朋友别再偏执 好好喝酒
Tell your friend to dial down the paranoia and have a drink.
我还觉得他不够偏执呢
I don't think he's being paranoid enough.
你不会也这样吧
Not you too.
你的冰块没了
You're out of ice.
我自作主张做了一本小册子
Now, I have taken the liberty of drawing up a pamphlet.
主题是 国会还没注意到
The subject: Congress unaware of a little thing
有个东西叫宪法第一修正案
called the First Amendment.
他们当然知道 只是不放在眼里
They're aware of it. They just don't give a shit.
他们只在乎这场美妙的新战争
All they care about is this nice new war of theirs.
他们热爱战争 这场战争正合他们的意
These guys love war and this is a great one,
因为既含糊不清 又恐怖而昂贵
'cause it's vague and it's scary and it's expensive.
赞成的就是英雄 反对的就是叛徒
Anybody for it is a hero
and anybody against it is a traitor.
正是如此 谢谢
IAN: Exactly, thank you.
亚伦 别在画旁吸烟
Arlen, not near the paintings.
别天真地以为他们拍完宣传影片就算了
And if you think this is about the movies, you're an idiot.
我决定深入敌方阵营
Which is why
I'm going to have a little chat with the other side.
你不会是指守护美国理想电影联盟吧？
You don't mean the Alliance, do you?
正是
I do.
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
艾迪 他们是演员 作家和导演
Eddie, they're all actors and writers and directors,
就像我们一样
just like us.
他们是纳粹 只是太过小气不愿买制服
They're Nazis. They're just too cheap to buy the uniforms.
他们把国会议员都请来了
They invited Congress out here.
他们不就是山姆·伍德和赫达·霍珀吗？
And are they all Sam Woods and Hedda Hoppers?
不要妖魔化我们不了解的人
Please, let's not demonize people we don't really know.
我赞成
I say we go for it.
你知道 他们请到谁来演讲吗？
And you know who you're gonna be talking to there, don't you?
各位女士先生 欢迎约翰·韦恩
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. John Wayne.
我想谈谈一个我热爱的地方
I wanna say one thing about a place I love.
不 不是好莱坞
No, not Hollywood.
我喜欢好莱坞 但我更热爱美国
I like Hollywood, but I love America.
美国代表的就是自由
WAYNE: And when we talk about America,
I'm talking about freedom.
不惜加入世界大战也要捍卫到底
The kind of freedom we just fought a world war to save.
想加入共产党？那就去吧
You want to be a communist? Go be a communist.
但我在华府的朋友
But some friends of mine in Washington
认为你们必须回答几个问题
think you got some questions to answer.
我真不晓得 他这么会说话
I never knew he was this good.
如果你们还想加入共产党…
WAYNE: You still want to be a commie...
- 因为他不是在表演 这才是他 - 去莫斯科吧
- 'Cause he's not acting. That's him. - go be one in Russia.
去加入莫斯科大剧院芭蕾舞剧团吧
But off you go and enjoy the Bolshoi Ballet.
先生 想了解宪法第一修正案吗？
Excuse me, sir, would you like to read about the First Amendment?
- 学习一点新知 - 你知道自己的权利吗？
- Sir, a little education. - You know your rights?
介绍宪法第一修正案的小册子
Pamphlet on the First Amendment.
- 只是份轻松读物 - 旅途愉快
- A little light reading. - Travels well.
谢谢你 山姆
Well, thank you, Sam.
再见
Do svidanya.
印小册子是要钱的
It costs money to print those.
想了解宪法第一修正案吗？
How'd you like to learn
about the First Amendment?
这简直是场恶梦
This is a nightmare.
达顿
Dalton.
赫达 晚安
Oh, Hedda. Good evening to you.
亲爱的艾迪
Eddie, darling!
赫达
Hedda.
新帽子？
New hat.
每天都要换一顶
Ah, daily, darling, daily.
你最近有去看电影吗 达顿？
Been to the movies lately, Dalton?
杜克 你们说他是不是棒极了？
Duke. Now, wasn't he magnificent?
我只是说出该说的话 你好 艾迪
Just saying what needs saying. Hi, Eddie.
你好 杜克
Duke.
听说你和朋友们印了本小册子
I hear you and your pals got a pamphlet.
- 有人拿吗？- 还没
- Any takers? - Not yet.
你想拿一本吗？我们是共产党员
Uh, would you like one, sir? We're communists.
他是剧作家
He's a writer.
这里没有人会拿你们的册子
You won't get any takers. Not here, anyway.
为什么？
Oh, why is that?
上面只说国会没有权力调查
All it says is that Congress has no right to investigate
我们给谁投票 去哪里祷告
how we vote or where we pray,
以及调查我们的思想言行和电影制作
what we think, say or how we make movies.
你好 我叫达尔顿·特朗勃
Hello, I'm Dalton Trumbo.
只要国会认定是威胁 就有权力查到底
Congress has the right to go after anything they think is a threat.
我们反对这样 重点是…
Well, that's where we disagree and that's the point.
我们都应该有犯错的权利
We both have the right to be wrong.
想谈权利 先告诉我你站在哪一边
You wanna talk about rights, first tell me whose side you're on.
俄国已经没有朋友了
Russia's no friend, not anymore.
你们赶快清醒吧
You'd better wake up.
因为新时代已经到来了
'Cause it's a new day. A new day!
然后呢？
And?
或许这时代不适合你这种人
And maybe it's not for your kind.
我这种人？哪一种？
My kind? What kind is that?
不明白我们如何打赢大战的人
The kind that has no idea why we just won a war.
真有趣 这是你第二次提及战事
It's curious, that's the second time you mentioned that.
我以前在冲绳当战地记者
See, I was a war correspondent in Okinawa.
赫达的儿子被派驻在菲律宾
Hedda's son was stationed in the Philippines.
艾迪在欧洲的战争情报局工作
Eddie was in Europe with the Office of War Information.
你当时在哪里服役呢？
Where did you serve again?
你想说什么？
You trying to say something?
没什么 杜克
No, Duke, he wasn't.
如果你在二战中也有战功
If you're going to talk about World War II as if you personally won it,
就请说清楚你被派驻何处
let's be clear where you were stationed.
你在片场 化着妆 射空包弹
On a film set, shooting blanks, wearing makeup.
如果你要揍我 我想先拿下眼镜
And if you're going to hit me, I would like to take off my glasses.
杜克 我们走
Duke, come on. Let's get out of here.
谢谢你 达顿 我的下个专栏有东西写了
Thank you, Dalton. My next column just wrote itself.
幸好你不想妖魔化任何人
It's a good thing you didn't want to demonize anybody
否则事情就尴尬了
or else that could have been awkward.
曼尼不会说"多情"这个字
Manny wouldn't say "amorous."
等等
Hang on one second.
保罗 请给我二包烟
Paul, two packs, please.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here you are. - Thank you.
钱给你
Here you go.
天啊 她真是无所不在
Good God, she's everywhere.
这份合约将让你成为好莱坞薪酬最高的编剧
Your next deal's gonna make you the highest-paid writer in Hollywood.
也就是全世界收入最高的剧作家
Which will make you the highest-paid writer in the world.
这是你应得的
You earned it.
你深信自己写出的快乐结局
You don't just write happy endings, you actually believe them.
所以观众才会买单
That's what people pay to see.
米高梅也才会雇用你 是吧 路易？
That's why you belong here at MGM. Right, L.B.?
我不想让你们太容易得逞 那我在哪儿签名？
I hate to make the wooing too easy for you, but where do I sign?
只有一个条件
Just one thing.
如想替我工作
If you're gonna work for me,
就不要再让我看到这种东西
I never, ever want to see anything like this again.
不会的 我保证
You won't. I promise.
很好
Good.
只要你不再读赫达霍珀的专栏
Just stop reading Hedda Hopper.
路易跟你说了什么？
So, what did L.B. say then?
别再提了
Jesus, don't.
我一直食不下咽 我的工作还不够辛苦吗？
I haven't eaten since. My job's not hard enough?
一点也不累
Your job is not hard at all.
你觉得在爆出新闻后 说服梅尔签下你很容易么？
You think getting Mayer to sign you after those headlines was easy?
公司提供破纪录的三年合约 供你在纸上胡说八道
You have a record-breaking three-year contract to make shit up.
不用谢我了
You're welcome.
亲爱的 现在不是时候
Oh, honey, not now.
拜托 妈
Please, Mom?
她真的可以
She really can.
- 请她表演 - 可以怎样？
- Ask her! - Can what?
克莉欧 是真的吗？
Cleo, is this true?
你们瞧
Watch this.
- 特朗勃… - 来啊
- Trumbo... - Come on.
你这是在向我挑战
Of course, you realize this means war.
大家注意
Behold!
我有个非凡的母亲
I had a very unusual mother.
也就是 星妈
Translation: stage mother.
杂技演员的悲惨童年
The misspent youth of a child acrobat.
天啊 你参加了多久的演出？
My God, how long were you in show business?
直到我15岁 基本上算是强迫劳动
Till I was 15, but it was more show forced-labor.
- 厉害 - 真精彩
- Bravo! - Brilliant!
达尔顿·特朗勃先生？
Mr. Dalton Trumbo?
是我
Yes?
我们华盛顿见
I'll see you in Washington.
传票
祝你们野餐愉快
Enjoy your picnic.
我们走
Let's go, boys.
遵命 史崔普林先生
Yes, Mr. Stripling, sir.
我们发出了19张传票
Nineteen subpoenas have been issued to those we believe
传唤知悉好莱坞内共党阴谋的人
have knowledge of the ongoing communist threat in Hollywood.
什么阴谋？
What kind of threat is that?
1947年 九月
企图败坏民主价值
A conspiracy to corrupt democratic values
并推翻这个国家
and bring about the overthrow of this nation.
利用电影？
Using movies?
你知道是哪部吗？
Any movie in particular or...
电影是人类史上最具影响力的工具
Movies are the most powerful influence ever created.
而隐身幕后的叛徒已染指电影
And they are infested with hidden traitors.
众议院非美活动调查委员会成立
The House Un-American Activities Committee has been formed to investigate
调查好莱坞中可疑的共党分子
alleged communists working in Hollywood.
摄影机和一队记者记录了现场的情景
The newsreel cameras and an army of newspapermen are on hand.
罗纳德·里根 演员公会主席
里根先生你是否知悉
Mr. Reagan, has it been reported to you
有一小群人 或多或少
There has been a small group more or less following the tactics
和共产党有些接触
that we, uh, associate with the Communist Party.
你认为他们是破坏分子吗？
And would you refer to them as a disrupting influence?
他们有时试图成为破坏分子
I would say that, at times, they have attempted to be a disruptive influence.
你认为电影界
Do you believe that the motion picture industry
已尽力不成为
is doing everything it can to rid itself
颠覆美国的势力吗？
of subversive un-American influences?
洛伊布鲁尔 国际戏剧舞台工作者联盟西岸代表
不 共产党员无所不在
No. Communists are everywhere.
他们直接向莫斯科汇报
They report directly to Moscow.
山姆·伍德 导演 守护美国理想电影联盟共同创办人
煽动共产主义的人在许多场合
On numerous occasions, communist agitators have tried hard
试图让我们沦陷于赤色思潮
to steer us into the red river.
但我们的立场坚定不移
We had a little too much weight for that.
你能指出几位煽动分子吗？
Will you name a few of these agitators?
欧文·皮切尔
Well, Irving Pichel,
艾迪华·狄米屈克 法兰克·杜托
Edward Dmytryk, Frank Tuttle.
罗伯特·泰勒 演员
若由我作主
If I had my way about it,
就把他们全送回俄国
they'd all be sent back to Russia
或是其他不毛之地
or some other unpleasant place.
我们得在三天内出面作证
We get our chance to testify in three days.
而这会损害我们的名誉
And what we're about to do won't make us too popular.
就算我们被人诋毁 那又如何？
Okay, so we get slandered and then what?
就用你的方式回答他们每一个问题
You answer every question they ask in your own way.
那就别跟他们抬杠
So, don't tell them shit.
说得好
Beautifully put.
你知道他们给我们起的罪名吗？
Well, you know what they call that?
知道
Yes.
我们十之八九会被指为藐视国会
In all likelihood, we'll be cited for contempt of Congress.
我们会被审判
There will be a trial.
我没听错吧？
What am I missing here?
我只听到了坐牢
All I'm hearing is jail.
不见得
Not necessarily.
在低等法庭我们应该会输
In a lower court, yes, we'll most likely lose.
- 但上诉之后 - 一定能成功
- But on appeal... - It'll work.
最高法院大法官九人中有五人是自由派
The Supreme Court is a five-to-four liberal majority.
他们认为委员会违宪
They think this committee is unconstitutional.
不除不快
They want it killed.
听起来不错
Sounds great.
但我退出
I'm out.
妮琪再见
Niki.
你们的计划我承担不起
Look, I can't afford this stuff you guys are talking about.
包括上诉最高法院以及法律费用
The Supreme Court and legal fees...
桃乐丝一定不会同意
You know, Dorothy's not gonna...
我的情况已不乐观
I mean, things already aren't great, but you know...
若再赌上所有积蓄 她会带孩子走人
If I dump all my savings into that, she's gone with the kids.
我帮你出
I'll cover you.
开销 旅费 诉讼费全由我付
Expenses, travel, legal fees, everything.
可是你明明不喜欢我
You don't even like me.
我喜欢你 是你不喜欢我
I like you fine. You don't like me.
你知道吗 我不相信你
No, you know what it is? I don't trust you.
不用我提 你也会继续说下去
Well, I'd say go on, but I'm afraid you will.
我知道自己有几两重
Look, I know what I am. Okay?
我当然希望举国上下焕然新生
I want this whole country
to be different, top to bottom.
若由我作主 没有人家里能有一座湖
If I get what I want, nobody gets their own lake.
这样的人生多无趣
Well, that would be a very dull life, don't you think?
对你而言是如此
Yeah, for you.
但造湖工人不这么认为
Not for the guys who built this.
或许是我错了 但从我们认识以来
If I'm wrong, tell me, but ever since I've known you,
你言论激进
you talk like a radical.
却仍过着富裕生活
But you live like a rich guy.
你没搞错
That is true.
我不觉得你会为了做正确的事牺牲这一切
I don't think you're willing to lose all of this just to do the right thing.
我反对殉教 也不打没胜算的仗
Well, I despise martyrdom and I won't fight for a lost cause.
没错
So you're right.
我不愿失去一切 尤其是孩子们
I'm not willing to lose it all. Certainly not them.
但我愿意赌一把
But I am willing to risk it all.
我是激进分子和有钱人的综合体
That's where the radical and the rich guy make a perfect combination.
激进分子依循耶稣的纯洁教诲奋战
The radical may fight with the purity of Jesus.
而有钱人则因撒旦的奸巧获胜
But the rich guy wins with the cunning of Satan.
够了
Oh, shit.
怎样？
What?
拜托你闭嘴 好吗？
Just please shut up. Please.
你要我做什么都可以
I'll do whatever you want.
只求你别再跟我说这些鬼话
Just please don't say shit like that anymore.
我无法保证
I can't guarantee that.
传唤的19人中 有10人抵达华盛顿
In Washington, 10 of the original 19 subpoenaed
开始在非美活动调查委员会面前作证
began their testimony before the House Un-American Activities Committee.
特朗勃先生 请举起右手
Mr. Trumbo, raise your right hand.
请宣誓 接下来所说的
Do you solemnly swear the testimony you are about to give
句句属实
is the truth, the whole truth, nothing but the truth so help you God?
我发誓
I do.
请坐
Sit down, please.
特朗勃先生 接下来我会问你一些问题
Mr. Trumbo, now I shall ask you a series of various questions
你只需要回答是或不是
all of which can be answered with a yes or a no.
我想回答是或不是 就会回答
Well, I shall answer yes or no if I please to answer.
我会回答自己想说的话
I shall answer in my own words.
不是每个问题都能用或否来回答
Many questions can be answered yes or no
除非对方是白痴或奴隶
only by a moron or a slave.
够了
That's enough!
你拒绝回答问题吗？
Are you refusing to answer the question?
主席 你的任何问题我都不会拒答
Mr. Chairman, I will refuse to answer none of your questions.
你现在或曾经是否加入过共产党？
Are you now or have you ever been
a member of the Communist Party?
我想提出证物
May I introduce to evidence...
不行 违反规则
No. No! You are out of order!
- 证据就是我写的剧本 - 不行
- my work, my screenplays... - No, no, no, no, no, no.
你可能依此做出这样的判断
by which you are making this determination?
一切由主席裁决
No, the chair will rule.
- 但这是关键 - 不行 没有时间
- It's critical to... - No, just a minute.
你的剧本太长了
Your screenplays are too long.
这句话我以前也听过
I've heard that before.
你现在或曾经是否加入过共产党？
Are you now or have you ever been a member of the Communist Party?
你指控我有罪？
Am I accused of a crime?
你没有回答问题
You're not asking the questions.
若是如此 我有权与指控我的
If so, I believe I have the right to be confronted
证据与证人对质
with any evidence that supports this question.
你拒绝回答问题么？
Are you refusing to answer the...
我想看看你的证据
I should very much like to see what you have.
是吗？我马上会拿给你看
Oh, you would? You will see very soon!
很好
Good!
证人请离席
The witness is excused.
你认为委员会有权强迫证言
You believe this committee has the right to compel testimony.
请你离席
You are dismissed, sir! Witness is dismissed!
你指控一个人的思想有罪
To indict opinion, to criminalize thought...
警卫 带他下去
Guard, take him out!
- 但你没有这样的权利 - 肃静
- but that right does not exist, sir! - Order!
上帝会在关键时刻帮助我们
And the moment it does, God help us all!
这就是典型的共产党策略！
This is typical communist tactic!
美国也开始办集中营了
This is the beginning of an American concentration camp!
肃静
Order!
请报上姓名
Uh, state your name, please.
亚伦赫德 我是剧作家
Arlen Hird. I'm a screenwriter.
如果你不回答我的问题
You understand, sir, that if you don't answer my questions,
将因藐视国会而遭羁押
I can hold you in contempt of Congress?
我还没有拒绝回答吧？
I didn't refuse yet, did I?
你现在或曾经是否加入过共产党？
Are you now or have you ever been
a member of the Communist Party?
我很乐意回答
Well, I'd like to answer you, Congressman,
但我得先问问我的医生
but I need to consult with my physician.
- 医生？- 是的
- Your physician? - Yes.
我不明白
I don't understand.
看他是否能动手术 切除我的良心
To find out if he can surgically remove my conscience.
他们都是敌意证人
This is a hostile witness.
这就是典型的共产党策略
This is typical communist tactics.
亚伦 你怎么了？
Arlen. Arlen, what is it?
我得了癌症
It's cancer.
什么？
What?
天啊
Jesus...
你知道多久了？
How long have you known?
- 三个月前 - 才几个月？
- Three months. - Months?
你有接受治疗吗？
Are you receiving treatment?
我不喜欢那些治疗法
Uh, I don't like the options.
我得了肺癌
It's lung cancer.
开不开刀都一样糟
Bad if you operate, bad if you don't.
我能帮上什么忙吗？
Well, is there anything I can do for you?
你帮不上忙 我得的是癌症
No! No, it's cancer.
是 但是
Yeah, but...
拜托
Jesus.
你想帮忙 就确保这计划成功
You want to do something? Make sure this plan works.
我已别无选择
I'm out of options.
好莱坞十君子被指控藐视国会
我们年轻时 自以为神通广大
We were so young. We thought we knew everything.
我们确实是
We did.
不 我不是
No, not me.
年轻时我还不知道自己多爱演戏
No, I didn't realize how much I loved it all
直到上年纪后戏约越来越少才明白
until I reached a certain age, and the roles started drying up.
当时我想 我所钟情的事物
I remember thinking, "Now what do you do
若不再钟情于我 该怎么办？
"when you love something but it stops loving you back?"
挺身而战
You fight.
不 你要更深爱它 直到它向你投降
No, no, no. You love it more until it surrenders.
赫达 你一直在米高梅和我心里
Hedda, you never left MGM or my heart.
你儿子最近好吗？
How's your boy?
很好
Fine. Fine.
还在海军？
Still in the navy?
是的 他是上尉了
Yes, he's First Lieutenant.
你养育了一个真正的英雄
You raised a real hero.
所以我想告诉他
Which is why I would like to tell him
我们也跟他一样 努力报效国家
that we are doing as much for this country as he is.
事情很复杂
It's complicated.
特朗勃等人手上都有合约
Trumbo, the others, all have contracts.
路易 你跟我一样白手起家打下江山
Oh, L.B., you helped build this business as did I.
怎能容许这些废物毁了一切？
We're not gonna watch these pissants defile it.
赫达 我经营电影片厂
I'm running a studio here, Hedda.
你以为每个员工我都喜欢吗？
You think I love every person on my payroll?
该长大了
Grow up.
不如我向3500万读者明确指出
Then how about I make it crystal clear to my 35 million readers
哪些好莱坞大佬不愿开除叛徒
exactly who runs Hollywood and won't fire these traitors?
不如写出这些赤色分子的本名吧
How about I name names? Real names.
雅各布·华纳 杰克·华纳 塞缪尔·戈尔德温 山姆·高德温
Jacob Warner, Jack Warner, Schmuel Gelbfisz, Sam Goldwyn.
当然还有你 路易·梅尔
And of course, yours. Lazar Meir.
请你放尊重点
You watch what you say to me!
40年前你还在犹太家乡挨饿
Forty years ago, you were starving in some shtetl.
世上最伟大国家接纳你 赐你金钱权势
The greatest country on Earth takes you in, gives you wealth, power.
但当我们需要你时 你却袖手旁观
But the second we need you, you do nothing.
在我读者的心目中
And that's exactly what my readers expect
犹太佬正是如此
from a business run by kikes.
滚出去
Get out!
路易 我很喜欢你
You know, L.B., I am fond of you.
我在这片厂度过许多愉快岁月
Some of my happiest years were spent on this lot.
当然不是在你办公室里
Not in your office, of course.
你总是想在沙发上要我
You were always trying to fuck me on the couch.
我只能尽力维护贞操 却仍差点失守
Me, trying to maintain my virtue... Barely.
但是斗转星移
But times change.
现在换我笑着上你了
Now I'd happily fuck you.
电影片厂开除共产党员
所有片厂一致同意开除好莱坞十君子
All studios unanimously agree to discharge the Hollywood Ten
不提供补偿 决议立即生效
without compensation, effective immediately.
所有片厂都不会雇用共产党员
No studio will ever employ a member of the Communist Party
或任何不愿配合对抗
or anyone refusing to cooperate
这可怕的新威胁的人
in our struggle with this terrible new menace.
20年来 他一直是影迷的最爱
He's been loved by film fans for almost 20 years.
但你们发现了吗？最近电影里都没有他
But have you noticed he hasn't been on-screen much lately?
票房不好？
Bad box office?
不 是政治立场不对
No. Bad politics.
对艾迪·华罗宾森而言 这真是个坏消息
Bad news indeed for Mr. Edward G. Robinson.
谢谢各位出席
Thank you so much for coming.
好莱坞十君子将为所有电影人上法庭
The Hollywood Ten are going to court for all of us.
这将会是场漫长昂贵的诉讼
It'll be long, expensive,
请尽量慷慨解囊 捐助辩护基金
so please give as much as you can to the defense fund.
感谢各位莅临
Thank you for coming.
- 晚安 亲爱的 - 祝你好运
- Good night, my dear. - Good luck.
- 晚安先生 谢谢 - 再见
- Good night, sir. Thank you. - Bye-bye.
聚会比不过去年
Well, this little gathering didn't quite have
那么有声有色 是吧？
the zip and zing of yesteryear, did it?
那些自由主义者在哪里？
Where are all the liberals all of a sudden?
去找律师或精神科医生了
At their lawyers' or psychiatrists'.
应该两者都有
Hmm, likely both.
捐给辩护基金
For the defense fund.
艾迪…
Eddie...
你最近有工作吗？
Have you been working?
生意有点清淡
Eh. It's a bit slow.
你卖了一幅画
You sold one.
梵高那幅
Oh, the van Gogh.
卖了个好价钱
Got a good price.
艾迪…
Eddie...
天啊 你看这数字 艾迪我不能收
Dear God, look at this. Eddie, I can't let you do...
我没事 收下吧
I'll be fine, kid, take it.
不行 实在太多了
No, it's too much. It's just too much.
收下
Take it.
艾迪 我…
Eddie, I...
你所做的一切…
Everything that you have...
他想说的是 他爱你
What he's trying to say is that he loves you.
我也爱他 脸上长疣的混蛋
I love him too, the warty son of a bitch.
要是你想贿赂陪审团 有人给莫奈的画出了高价
Got a great offer on the Monet if you want to bribe the jury.
美国政府控告达尔顿·特朗勃一案
In the matter of the United States v. Dalton Trumbo,
1949年6月 华盛顿特区
陪审团认定被告藐视国会罪名成立
we find the defendant guilty of contempt of Congress.
特朗勃先生
Mr. Trumbo! Mr. Trumbo!
我们车上见
I'll meet you in the car.
特朗勃先生 你是否藐视国会？
Mr. Trumbo, are you in contempt of Congress?
我当然看不起他们
Well, I have total contempt of this Congress.
只是我以为陪审团将理解为什么
I just thought the jury would see why.
最高法院会迅速驳回陪审团的裁定
The Supreme Court will drop kick
this verdict into speeding traffic
终结这出国会史上最羞耻的闹剧
and end the most shameful chapter
in Congressional history.
够了 没别的话可说
Now, that's it, boys. We have nothing else.
采访结束
No, we're done, we're done.
你的经济状况如何？
KENNY: How are you doing for money?
穷到喝西北风了 怎样？
Broke as a bankrupt's bastard. Why?
你欠我三万元 上诉费用还要加倍
Well, you owe me $30,000, and this appeal's gonna be twice that.
那我最好赶紧去开工赚钱
Well, I'd better get to work.
做什么？你没有能力做别的事
Doing what? You have no talent to do anything else.
好莱坞大反攻
NARRATOR: Hollywood fights back!
我是葛雷哥莱毕克
This is Gregory Peck.
美国已近乎歇斯底里
A state of near hysteria
指控所谓的共产党员
over so-called communists in this country
威胁国民自由
threatens the freedom of other citizens.
非美活动调查委员会则延续了此悲剧
So the Un-American Committee bears its tragic fruit.
我是露西·波儿
This is Lucille Ball.
我们都同意 应该捍卫美国宪法
All of us agree that the Constitution of the United States must be defended.
但使反对者噤声并非正当作为
But the way to do this is not by shutting up the man you disagree with.
我们必须捍卫对方表达且被聆听的权利
You must fight for his right to speak and be heard.
各项自由都是牵一发动全身
All civil liberties go hand in hand.
有一项沦陷 其他便岌岌可危
And when one goes, the others are weakened.
一柱垮塌
Just as a collapse of one pillar in a house
大厦将倾
would endanger the whole structure.
安公主 我从未和男人独处
过几天你就能回家了
We'll send you home in a couple of days.
听起来你还能活下去
Well, it sounds like you're going to live.
他们得治好我 才能送我进监牢
Yeah, they got me just well enough to go to prison.
你觉得如何？
How do you feel?
只能用一边肺呼吸 感觉只吸到一半
Breathing with one lung, which is half as good as two.
亚伦 我听说桃乐丝的事了
Look, Arlen, I heard about Dorothy.
没错 她离开了
Yeah, she took off.
她总是很会挑时间
Her timing was always amazing.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
是啊 她怎么能就这样远走高飞？
No, well, I know. I mean, how could you leave all this?
外头状况如何？
How's it going out there?
大家都很嫉妒你
Everyone envies you.
当然
Well, why wouldn't they?
我得到了苦窑里最棒的房间
I got the best room in the joint.
你一定知道 因为钱是你出的
You should know. You paid for it.
- 恭喜你 巴迪 - 谢谢各位
- Congratulations, Buddy. - Thank you, fellas.
罗斯国际影业
谁需要那些片厂？我完全独立自主
Who needs the studios? I am strictly independent.
有底片 有华尔街的资金
Got cans of film, wads of Wall Street dough,
还有最棒的老板 我自己
and my favorite boss, me. (ALL LAUGH)
干杯
Cheers. Cheers.
你这个疯子
And you, you crazy son of a bitch,
等这鬼官司结束 所有电影都交给你写
you're gonna write all of my movies once this Washington crap clears up.
怎么才能结束呢？
And how will that happen?
感谢老天 我不关心政治
I'm not political, thank Jesus.
如果他们传唤我 指控我 我会说
If they called me in, accused me, I'd just say,
抱歉 我不是故意的
"Yup, did it. Sorry, didn't mean it."
接着国会问你
So Congress then asks,
你是否曾加入民主党？
"Are you now or have you ever been a Democrat?"
我是民主党员 天啊 我觉得糟透了
I am and, God, I just feel awful about it.
然后他们会要你供出民主党员名单
Then they want the names of other Democrats.
例如比尔 厄尔 奈特和汤姆
Bill and Earl, Nate, Tom.
我会说 去吃屎吧
Then I say, "Go to hell."
真的吗？
Really?
有哪些银行愿意资助政府的敌人？
How many banks fund enemies of the state?
除非供出朋友的名字 否则拿不到钱
Your money's gone unless you give the names
of your friends here.
他们永远无法工作 但如此你才能存活
They'll never work again,
but it's the only way you ever will.
我们彼此相熟 包括我们的家人
We all know each other, our families.
我们是朋友
We're friends.
你会怎么做 巴迪？
What would you do, Buddy?
只有你
Only you.
会毁了别人一生最美好的一天
Piss on the best day of a guy's life.
只有你
Only you!
天啊
Christ's sakes.
"根据协议…"
According to the protocol set forth...
她会怎么说？
And what does she say?
公主会说什么？
What does the princess say?
可恶 烂透了
Shit... Shit!
"应该一点都不像才对"
Shouldn't be any likeness...
"这让我有点担心"
It concerns me a little bit.
早安 妮可拉
Oh, good morning, Nikola.
我以为你不能写剧本了
I thought you weren't allowed to write anymore.
不 只是剧本上不能有我的名字
Ah. No. No, just not allowed to put my name on it,
或直接付钱给我
or get paid.
这是什么状况？
How does that work?
状况不太好
Not very well.
这故事很有趣 轻松又浪漫
It's funny. It's breezy and romantic.
是谁写的？
Who wrote it?
你写的 老弟
You did, old boy.
我的剧本写上你的名字
You stick your name on my labor,
交给公司就成了
hand it in to your studio and we're in business.
我没被传唤或列入黑名单只是侥幸
Look, it is just dumb luck that I wasn't subpoenaed and blacklisted myself.
下一波审讯即将展开
The hearings are going to start up again soon.
我也可能会被停工或解雇
I'm going to get called and canned.
那手脚要更快
Well, then quick, lad.
剧本卖成了 我们五五分帐
Let's sell this little beauty and split the take, 50-50.
荒唐 我收一成就好
Ridiculous. I'll take 10%.
你收二成 不 三成 这是我的底线
You'll take 20. No, 30! And that's my final offer.
你是全世界最烂的生意人
You're the worst businessman ever.
我讨厌这片名
I hate the title.
我也是
Me too.
哪里不好？
Really? What's wrong with it?
- 《公主与乡巴佬》？ - 是啊
- The Princess and the Peasant. - Yes.
拜托 听起来像出偶剧
God, please, Trumbo, it sounds like a puppet show.
那就改掉吧
Well, then, change it.
改了
I did.
真的？你觉得这个名字更好？
Really? You think this title's better?
《罗马假日》
Roman Holiday.
我喜欢
I like it.
谁让你加入的？
Who invited you?
我
I did.
她是我最喜欢的特朗勃家庭成员
She's my favorite Trumbo.
我要立法
I'm introducing legislation
1949年9月
在此国家危急时刻
so in the event of a national emergency,
所有共产党员都会被送进俘虏收容所
all communists will be sent to internment camps.
总统支持此案么？
And the president supports this?
他最好能支持
He better.
帕奈尔 我们得谈谈你的员工
Parnell, I need to speak to you privately about your employees.
我先失陪了
Excuse me, gentlemen.
这些都是我家乡的合法支薪员工
As I said, Bob, these are legitimate salaried employees from my home state.
但你没告诉我 他们都是你的亲戚
What you didn't tell me is that every one of them is a relative.
这完全合法
Which is completely legal.
可是他们都没缴税
Except that none of them pay taxes.
等你的律师到场后再说吧
Don't say anything else without a lawyer.
不
No.
特朗勃太太 你好
Mrs. Trumbo! Hi.
杰夫
Jeff.
太太 你该付我工钱了
Ma'am, I gotta get paid.
抱歉
Oh. I'm so sorry.
我的人都要养家
I got men with families.
我丈夫无法工作
My husband hasn't been able to get any work.
我们四处欠债
We owe everyone.
- 太太 拜托 - 真的很抱歉
- Ma'am, please. - I'm so...
克莉欧 我们有钱了
Cleo, we're rich!
拿去吧 杰夫
There you are, Jeffrey.
你们的生活真刺激
You people sure live exciting lives.
谢谢你的帮忙
Well, I thank you. Appreciate it.
也谢谢你贝蒂
Thank you, Betty!
我们成功了
We did it, Cleo!
派拉蒙买了《罗马假日》
We sold Roman Holiday! Paramount.
亲爱的 伊恩刚刚…
Our beloved Ian is just...
怎么了？
Why, what's the matter?
拉特利奇大法官死了
Judge Rutledge died.
上个月死的是墨菲
No, no, that was Judge Murphy who died last month.
拉特利奇也死了
And Rutledge.
昨晚过世
Last night.
维利·拉特利奇死于脑溢血 终年55岁
别担心
Oh, now...
一切都会没事的
Everything will be all right. You'll see.
自由派大法官不占多数
Without a liberal majority on the court,
上诉将被驳回
our appeal's gonna be denied.
也就是说 我们都要准备坐牢
Meaning we should all be prepared to go to prison.
就算从头来过 我也不会改变任何决定
I wouldn't change anything going back. Not one thing.
一年后我们再问问彼此吧
Let's ask each other in a year.
1950年6月
解救好莱坞十君子
帮我个忙
Will you do me a favor?
我不在时帮我保管这个
Hold on to this while I'm gone.
谢谢你 亲爱的
Thank you, dear.
每天都要逗妈妈笑
Your mother needs to laugh at least once a day.
一言为定？
Deal?
好的
Okay.
我的小可爱去哪了？
Where's that little pumpkin seed?
- 敬好莱坞十君子 - 谢谢
- To the Hollywood Ten! - Thank you.
敬好莱坞十君子
To the Hollywood Ten!
你们是英雄
You're heroes!
爱许兰 肯塔基州
28美分 金色打火机
28 cents. Gold lighter.
皮夹 烟盒
Wallet. Cigarette case.
举手
Raise your hands.
张开嘴巴 张大点
Open your mouth. Wider.
头转右边 转左边
Turn your head to the right. To the left.
头往后仰
Tilt your head back.
腿张开
Spread your legs.
拿起阴囊 拉起来
Grab your sack and skin it back.
转身
Turn around.
拨开屁股
Spread your cheeks.
蹲下 咳嗽
Squat. Cough.
转身
Turn around.
出去
Move out.
下一位
Next!
1950年8月
典狱长要我好好处置
So the warden says I gotta do right.
他想要更好的工作？
Boy want a better job?
我就派他去管该死的储藏室
I put him in charge of the whole goddamn supply room.
因为我知道典狱长不知道的事
'Cause I know something the warden don't.
货都搬下来了 卡车司机要我们签收
Truck's unloaded. Driver needs a signature.
其实 他需要签在这里
Actually, uh, he needs it right here.
如果你需要任何协助
You know, if, uh... If you need any help,
我以前在烘焙坊做进出货
I used to run shipping at a... At a bakery.
我听说你是剧作家
Heard you's a writer.
身兼二职
Well, that too.
也是共产党员
And a commie.
你们这些人有什么毛病？
What the fuck is wrong with you people?
美国是个伟大的国家
This is a great country.
我同意
Agreed.
你会打字吗？
You type?
停
Stop.
但愿我能识字
Well, now, if only I could read it.
"退还货品协议"
"Protocol as to return of goods.
"应准备一式三份文件"
"There shall be triplicate copies of Form 14-A filed
"归档于储藏室 运送处与典狱长室"
"with Supply, Shipping and Office of the Warden."
你以为我会请你教我识字
You think you're gonna teach me the alphabet
然后跟你握手说
and I'm gonna shake your hand all grateful and say,
"感谢改变我的一生"
"Thank you, Mr. Trumbo. You done change my life, sir.
"我不会忘记你"
"I'll never forget you."
我杀了想抢我酒吧的白人 被判20年
I got 20 years for killing me a white man who tried to rob my bar.
我不介意再干一次
I did it and I'd do it again.
我会搞死瞧不起我的人
You look down on me and I will fuck you up like you've never been fucked up
让你享受在比佛利山庄没吃过的苦头
in your whole bullshit Beverly Hills life.
我现在要努力申请假释
Now I'm here trying to build my time and make parole.
你要帮我吗？
You wanna help make that happen?
欢迎来到该死的储藏室 同志
Welcome to fucking Supply, Comrade.
克莉欧 我不计算过了几天或几小时
Dear Cleo, I don't count the days or hours...
而是数秒度日
I count the seconds.
有时我以为自己将因厌倦或恐惧而死
Sometimes I think I'll die of boredom. Other times, fear.
这里并不可怕
Not of this place.
目前所有挑战我都能克服
So far, its challenges are all surmountable.
我不怕与日俱增的无聊
Augmented by days of lovely boredom.
也不怕在丑恶不幸的打斗后平静醒来
So flat and calm in the wake of all that churning ugly luckless battle.
新一波好莱坞共产分子审讯开始
不 我怕的是出去之后
No, my fear is for what will happen when I get out.
不知道家庭和国家会变成什么模样
To our family and our country.
并非所有消息都值得忧虑
Not all the news is worrisome.
有些事情超乎想像
Some reminds me that what the imagination can't conjure
却轻易抖落于现实之中
reality delivers with a shrug.
现实开了一个大玩笑
And reality has delivered in all its beatific wonder
把约翰·帕奈尔·汤马斯送进监狱里
to the federal penal system, J. Parnell Thomas,
他因逃漏税入狱
convicted of tax evasion.
瞧瞧我们 二只笼中鸟
Well, look at us. Just a couple of jailbirds.
只不过 你是真的犯了罪才进来
Except you actually committed a crime.
撇开一切种种
Yet in all this,
我已是不幸之人中最幸运的了
I know I'm the luckiest unlucky man ever to live,
你和孩子们是我的温暖 食粮
because you and the children warm, feed,
衣被 平静与活力
clothe, pacify, and rejuvenate me
因为你们永远都在我心中
by never leaving my heart.
爱你的7551号囚犯
Love, Prisoner Number 7551.
子弹 炸药和拳头无法打败日本鬼子
We're not gonna take that hill from the Japs with bullets, bombs or fists.
是的
Yeah!
让他们血流成河吧
We're gonna take it with blood.
流血多的一方就输
Whoever spills more, loses.
我们不会输的
And we don't lose.
对不对？
Do we?
对
No!
你输了
You lose.
我就知道
That's what I thought.
你认识约翰·韦恩？
You know John Wayne?
认识
I do.
他是怎样的人？
What's he like?
你们一定会喜欢彼此
You'd love each other.
很美吧？来吧
Isn't he beautiful? Okay.
妈 我想到一个新招
Mom, I got a new one. Huh?
等一下
Okay, wait.
过来 你会吓到那匹马
Come on, you're gonna scare the horse.
妈 快点过来
Mom, you'd better come quick!
艾迪·华罗宾森 你是否现在或曾经？
Edward Robinson, are you now or have you ever been
为共产党员
a member of the Communist Party?
我现在不是 以前也没加入过
I'm not now, sir, nor have I ever been a member of that party.
我一直是信奉自由主义的民主党员
I have always been a Liberal Democrat.
但多年来 在你家中
But in your home over the years,
曾举行过多次政治集会
there have been political meetings attended by those
参与者都是共产党员
that we now know to be communists.
是的 我现在才搞清楚
Yes, sir. Yes, that has now been made clear to me.
特克萨卡纳州立监狱
我家举行过无数活动与募款
There were tremendous activities and fundraisers...
就在战时
that went on in my house during the war.
当时我不清楚
I did not know then
他们隶属什么组织
all of their true affiliations
进行什么工作
or the work that they were up to.
我从没想过他们可能是共产党员
It never entered my mind
that any of these people were communists.
他们愚弄 利用 欺骗了我
I was duped and used. I was lied to.
谁利用你？
But who used you?
呃…
Well, um...
或许就是这股邪恶势力策动所有组织
These sinister forces who probably ran these organizations.
请说出你知道的人名
Oh, tell us the individuals that you have reference to.
罗宾森先生？
Mr. Robinson?
有艾伯特·马尔兹
Well, uh, you had Albert Maltz.
法兰克·杜托 还有其他人
I knew Frank Tuttle and that other fellow.
被他们称为政委的高层人士是
That top fellow who they say is the, uh, commissar out there.
亚伦·赫德？
Arlen Hird?
没错 亚伦·赫德
Yes, yes, Arlen Hird.
我不认识迪麦特雷克
I didn't know Dmytryk at all.
我现在成了政委
I'm a commissar now.
伊恩·麦克连·汉特 以及…
Ian McLellan Hunter... and
达尔顿·特朗勃
Dalton Trumbo.
谢谢你 罗宾森先生
Thank you, Mr. Robinson.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
主席 我没有问题了
Mr. Chairman, I have no further questions.
在这里 谁敢这样打小报告
Snitch like that in here,
你就死定了
you end up fucking dead.
守护美国理想电影联盟
主席 约翰·韦恩
艾迪尽了责任 应当回到工作岗位
Eddie ought to go back to work. He did what he had to.
不行 他是被逼才开口的
No, no, he did what he was forced to do.
重点是他说了
Well, the point is, he did it.
勇敢的男人与男孩们 正与共产主义作战
Brave men and boys are fighting this battle against communism.
我们难以想像他们做了何等牺牲
They are sacrificing in ways we can't even imagine.
而你却担心这个混帐的电影事业？
And you wanna talk about some asshole's movie career?
我多希望艾迪及其党羽们的死
I'd see Eddie Robinson and everyone like him dead
能换取朝鲜战场一个男孩的性命
if it'd bring back one boy from Korea. Just one.
艾迪都合作了
So what are you saying?
难道不能得到好处？
Guys like Eddie cooperate and get nothing?
这样不对
That isn't right.
说话小心点 杜克
Careful, Duke.
什么意思 赫达？
Or what, Hedda?
要是我不小心会怎样？
If I'm not careful, what?
我不晓得原来你这么软趴趴
I had no idea you were such a softie.
是啊 我就是柔软好抱
That's me all right. All cuddles.
以你为荣
Proud of ya, Eddie.
这事不容易 但你做得很好
Wasn't easy, I know. But you did good.
谢谢 杜克
Thanks, Duke.
我会致电片厂 片约将蜂拥而至
I'm gonna call the studios. The offers will pour in.
好的
Sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
美国史上和平时期最大的间谍案
One of the greatest peacetime spy dramas
已迈入高潮 罗森堡夫妇被判处死刑
reaches its climax,
as Julius and Ethel Rosenberg are sentenced to death
因为他们将核弹机密泄漏给苏俄
for revealing atomic secrets to Soviet Russia.
威斯康辛州的初级参议员 约瑟夫·麦卡锡
The junior senator from Wisconsin, Joseph McCarthy,
正加速调查可疑的共党分子
is ramping up his investigation into alleged communists he believes
他们可能已渗透入政府 军队和学校
are infiltrating our government, our military, and our schools.
敌人让叛徒和骗子
because the enemy has been able to get the traitors and dupes
潜入我们的政府进行工作
to do his work within our government.
在大学教职员中
One communist on the faculty
一个共产党员都不能留
of one university is one communist too many.
共产党员都是莫斯科间谍
人们必须忠诚 否则就是不忠诚
A man is either loyal or he's disloyal.
1951年4月
谢谢你 比利
Thank you, Billy.
他们来了
They're here! They're here!
他们到家了 爸爸
They're home! Dad!
巨人进攻
I'm being attacked by giants! Ah!
我的孩子怎么变得这么漂亮了
What have you beautiful creatures done with my little ones?
爸爸 我们好想你
Oh, Dad, we missed you.
- 克里斯多福 梅兹 - 你好 爸爸
- Christopher. Mitzi. - Hi, Dad.
天啊
My goodness.
妮可拉 瞧瞧你
Nikola, look at you.
她个子可真高
She got real tall.
这是口红吗？
Oh, is that lipstick?
爸…
Dad...
我好想念你们 你们每个人
Oh, I've missed you so much. All of you.
土地出售
真是抱歉…
Oh, I'm terribly sorry...
巴迪 你好吗？
Oh, Buddy! Well, how are you?
我对你无话可说
I got nothing to say to you.
监狱似乎让我们染上了瘟疫
Looks like prison has given us the plague.
是啊 巴迪·罗斯一直都这么讨人厌
Yeah, well, that Buddy Ross, he was always an asshole.
是啊
Yeah.
他日子也不好过
He's in trouble too.
- 三部电影都赔钱 - 真的吗？
- Three movies, three flops. - Oh, really?
他想出卖灵魂 却不知灵魂在哪里
Look at him. He's trying to sell his soul, but he can't find it.
希望他能撑到打完官司再破产
I just hope he stays afloat long enough to get the shit sued out of him.
是吗 谁告他？
Oh, really? By whom?
你 我和大家
By me and you and all of us.
天哪
Jeez...
用他们的资本主义对付他们
We use their capitalist system against them...
上民事法庭索赔
In civil court. We go after their money.
- 以报一箭之仇 - 不 不
- For what they did to us! - No. No. No.
要他们举手立誓
We make them swear under oath...
别说了 老天
No, no, no. Christ!
难道你在法庭待的时间还不够吗？
Haven't you spent enough time in court?
我可是受够了 老天爷
I know I have. Jesus Christ.
不然我们该怎么做？
Well, what else are we supposed to do?
做一件所有人以为我们做不到的事
We do the one thing everyone says we can't.
你是大剧作家 我们拍的都是烂片
Look, you're a great writer. We make shit.
金氏兄弟电影公司
我不懂要怎么合作
I don't see it.
金先生 我是剧作家
Mr. King, I'm a screenwriter.
如果我写不出烂片 我会挨饿的
If I couldn't write shit, I'd starve.
特朗勃 我们付不起你的片酬
Trumbo, we can't afford you.
那部片的剧本你们付了多少钱？
Well, how much did you pay for the script of that?
《恫村五虎》
Bad Men of Tombstone
1200元
$1,200.
好 我就写一部电影给你 1200元
All right. I'll write you a movie for $1,200, then.
而且不愿署名？
And you don't want your name on it?
才不是 是你们不想放我的名字
No, you don't want my name on it.
没错
You got that right.
特别是如果你还在从事那些活动
Especially if you're still, you know, up to stuff.
还没收手？
Are you?
这辈子脱不了身
Perpetually.
天啊
Jesus.
你有什么想法？
You got any ideas?
这个… 我刚刚出狱
Well, I just got out of prison.
何不拍部犯罪电影？
What about crime?
一位歹徒的崛起与没落
A story of a gangster, his rise and fall.
这种题材我看到过几次
I've seen that a few times.
因为容易赚钱啊
Because it always makes money.
好 我何时能收到？
All right, when do I get my goods?
三天内
Three days.
三天内写完一百页的剧本？
A 100-page screenplay in three days?
你想搞我吗？
Are you trying to fuck me?
你如果敢搞我 我就搞死你
'Cause if you fuck me, I will fuck you.
金先生 这句话我曾经听过
Mr. King, I've heard this speech.
牢里的人 肯定更有气势
It was better in jail.
不 老板
"No, boss...
他
"He..."
你在开什么玩笑？海米 快过来
Are you kidding me with this? Hymie, get out here!
海米 快雇用他 他是天才 写得太好了
Hymie, pay the man! He's a genius. Beautiful.
稍等 你看我们手头的剧本《沼泽杀手》
Wait a minute, look. We got Killer in the Swamp.
里头最棒的角色是沼泽
The best character's the swamp. Oh, oh.
《女子监狱》
Women in Prison.
女人穿内衣打架
Dames fighting in their underwear.
题材很棒 但写得烂透了
It's perfect, except it stinks.
还有吗 海米？
What else, Hymie?
海盗电影 但拍海太贵了
Pirates. Can't afford the ocean.
确实
That's it.
全部改写
Fix them all.
还有更多等着你
You want more, we got more. Oh, baby!
高地公园 加利福尼亚 1952年
你们觉得新家的环境如何？
So, what do you think of the new neighborhood?
- 我喜欢 - 很棒
- I like it. - Yeah, this is nice.
没错 爸
Yeah, Dad.
住在城里感觉一定很棒
It's gonna be good being in town.
你们瞧
Whoa, look at that!
- 喝点汽水吧 - 谢谢
- I brought you some lemonade. - Thank you.
辛苦了 还搬得动吗？
Hard work. You holding up okay?
- 没问题 - 没问题 谢谢
- Pretty good. - All right, thank you.
我们忘记拿毛巾了
We forgot the towels!
糟糕 等等我
Oh, shoot! Wait for me. Wait for me.
特朗勃家收
欢迎来到本社区 叛徒
梅兹…嘘…
Mitzi... Shh!
滚蛋
世上有许多愤怒却无知的人
Well, there are many angry and ignorant people in the world.
他们的繁殖速度似乎屡破纪录
They seem to be breeding in record numbers.
我们是一家人
Now, all we can do as a family
必须彼此陪伴 保持警惕
is stick together and remain vigilant.
1953年1月
罗马假日
编剧 伊恩·麦克连·汉特
"真理之口"
The Mouth of Truth.
传说如果说谎的人手伸进去
Legend is that if you're given to lying,
and you put your hand in there,
就会被咬掉
it'll be bitten off.
真可怕
Oh, what a horrid idea!
你来试试看
Let's see you do it.
你先来
没问题
Sure.
开玩笑的
Hello.
你这个人 怎么这样
You beast!
《罗马假日》票房大卖 好评连连
It's a huge hit. Great reviews.
我九个月没工作了 你呢？
I haven't worked in nine months. You?
难以糊口
Well, there aren't quite enough zeros
金氏兄弟给的酬劳太少
in a King Brothers' salary to survive,
但他们对剧本的需求 就像军队对卫生纸
but they need scripts like an army needs toilet paper.
不求品质 只求数量
Quality minimum, quantity maximum.
我原以为舍弃对电影的艺术追求
You'd think that when the artistic ambitions of a movie are non-existent,
剧本能轻易在一周内交出
the work would be tossed off in a week.
但要持续取悦二位弹珠台销售员
But consistently pleasing two former pinball salesmen
结果却是难上青天
turns out to be a high hurdle indeed.
我开始成了家里的陌生人
And I've become a stranger in my own house.
一周工作七天 每天18小时
Every workweek is seven days. Every day is 18 hours.
进度却越来越落后
Every minute, I'm further behind.
他们需要五个你
They need five of you.
问题是 这些左翼分子会写剧本？
Okay, the only question is, can these pinkos write?
短小精悍 穿灰西装的
Well, the dapper gentleman in the gray suit
是伊恩·麦克连·汉特
is Ian McLellan Hunter.
写《罗马假日》的人
Guy who wrote Roman Holiday.
最近被传唤的人
Guy who just got subpoenaed.
刚被提名奥斯卡奖的人
Guy who just got nominated for an Academy Award.
那桌人都被提名过
Everyone at that table's been nominated.
艾伯特·贝西 艾卓安·史考特 亚伦·赫德
There's Alvah Bessie, and Adrian Scott. Arlen Hird.
小文拉纳 艾伯特·马尔兹 以及…
And Ring Lardner, Jr. and Albert Maltz and...
这样吧
It'll be like this.
我来找写手合作
I'll find the writer and work with him.
对方提供剧本给我
He'll deliver the script to me.
够好我就交给你们
If it's good, I'll give it to you.
不够好我就改写
If it needs work, I'll fix it.
你们觉得满意再付钱
No one gets paid until you're happy.
这些剧作家 他们都是…
And these writers, they're... They're all...
他们都是黑…
I mean, they're all black...
黑名单
Blacklisted.
拜托 你也太胆小了吧
Jesus, you're such a chicken-shit.
我们正在和共产分子交战
You know, we're at war with the communists.
- 我们并没有 - 这是新型态的战争
- No we're not. - It's a new kind of war.
没错 根本不存在的战争 超新潮的
Yeah, if it doesn't exist, very new.
- 那罗森堡夫妇呢？- 他们怎么了？
- What about the Rosenbergs? - What about the Rosenbergs?
他们偷了核弹的秘密
They stole the atom bomb.
他们只是没有躲过眼线
They didn't steal it off a fucking camera truck.
我们既然已经雇了打手
So look, we bought a gorilla suit.
就要写出轰动世界的作品
We gotta use it.
好的
Well.
你原有五份工作
So, you had five jobs.
现在被我们拿走了 你怎么办？
And now we got them and now you got none?
我就有时间再去找五份工作和五个写手
Oh, now I'm free to get five more jobs and five more writers.
你们每个人如法炮制
And you each get five more jobs and five more writers and so on.
这样下去 我们就会垄断市场
To keep that going, we'd have to write every script in the business.
亚伦 你真狡诈
Oh, Arlen, what a devious lad.
谁想写出轰动世界的电影？
So who wants to write a gorilla movie?
谁不想？
Who doesn't?
我们接下来要在黑夜里
We now work at midnight
在浓雾中与陌生人做生意
in thick fog among strangers.
这只是一种形容
Not literally.
我们要经营家族事业
We're running a family business.
接上新的电话线后 接听电话时
We'll be adding new phone lines,
千万别说 这里是特朗勃家
and when answering, never say, "Trumbo residence."
我会用不同笔名和不同的制片人合作
I'll be writing for various producers under different names.
不论谁来电 记得来找我
Whomever they ask for, you come find me.
或留言
Or take a message.
喂
Hello?
约翰·亚伯特在吗？
Is John Abbott there?
他不在 方便留言吗？
No, sir, may I take a message?
不论何时都要有人应门
The door must be answered at all hours.
我来收莎莉·史塔波斐的邮件
Got a pickup for Sally Stubblefield.
可以请令堂签名吗？
Can I get your mom to sign?
谢谢
Thank you.
你们要学习听写 速记和打字
Dictation, shorthand and typing will be learned.
成年人则负担最重要的工作
Those of legal age will have one of the most important jobs imaginable.
秘密快递
Courier.
使命必达 且不能让人生疑
Scripts must be delivered to producers without raising suspicion.
有问题或担忧吗？
Any questions? Concerns?
- 妮可拉 请说 - 有时间表吗？
- Yes, Nikola. - Is there a schedule?
什么？
A what?
我得安排时间做作业
I need to know when I can do homework.
募款支持争取黑人投票权
And I'm part of a fundraising committee for Negro voting rights.
每周五 学生会还要开会
Plus, every other Friday, we have meetings for Student Council.
我必须…
I'm... I have to...
别担心 会有办法的 宝贝
Niki, we'll figure something out, sweetheart.
是吧？
Won't we?
人们持续抗争 近期最高法院
And protests continued as the Supreme Court may soon take up
南方不要黑鬼
可能得回应种族隔离政策
the issue of racial segregation.
南方城镇的黑人
Negros in Southern towns and cities
大量走上街头
have taken to the streets in large numbers.
当地执法者正加强控制
All under close scrutiny by local law enforcement.
许多未经证明的消息指出 可能发生暴动
There have been unconfirmed reports of disturbances and rioting.
但不确定发起暴动的是示威者
But it is not clear if the violence was initiated by protesters...
妮可拉
Nikola!
还是白人义务联防队
or white vigilante groups.
除了南方 整个国家
Beyond the South, through the nation...
好了 给你
Now, there you go.
只改了几个地方 错得不多
A few mistakes, not many.
不错
All right.
薪资最高的政府官员
all top-salaried government officials
应该全面公开他们的收入
should make a full public statement of their income...
今日节目到此结束
This concludes our program scheduled for today.
安非他命
谁是"葛拉汉·塔波"？
Which one is Graham Tauper?
写了《色情修女》
Nympho Nun.
是我
Oh.
干得好
Great job.
写《马戏团杀手》的艾伍德卡尔
Uh, Elwood Carr, Murder at the Circus.
需要改进 我猜到小丑是凶手了
It needs work. I knew the clown did it.
凶手永远都是小丑
It's always the clown.
《外星人与农庄女》是你写的？
So you are The Alien and the Farm Girl.
是的
Yeah.
你笔下的外星人谈论劳工权益
So you wrote the alien talking about the rights of the worker.
资本主义的病灶
The pathology of capitalism.
以及布尔乔亚的自满
The complacency of the bourgeoisie.
我根本看不懂 烂透了
I don't even know what it is and I fucking hate it.
我的创作理念是…
Well, the idea was to use the...
我付钱请你写的是
I paid you to write a script about
大头外星人在干草堆上女人的故事
a guy with a giant bug head shtupping a girl in a hayloft.
而你写了这些垃圾
And you write shit
会害我被传唤且名声扫地
that's gonna get me subpoenaed, and stinks!
重写
Fix it!
该死的法兰克金
Well, fuck Frank King.
我承诺要改写到他开心为止
I said, until he's happy, I'd rewrite.
你要为了这种垃圾开夜车？
So you're gonna stay up with that all night, for that crap?
为了什么
For what?
达到他的文学与政治标准？
To get it to his high literary and political standards?
这东西不该扯上任何政治标准
Well, it shouldn't be to anyone's political standards.
这是《外星人与农庄女》 拜托
It's The Alien and the Farm Girl, for Christ's sake.
你到底在想什么？
What the hell were you thinking?
我在想
I was thinking.
这就是我写作的初衷 写出重要的事物
That's why I'm a writer. To say things that matter.
你还记得吗？
Remember that?
我是曾入围普利兹奖的记者
I was a reporter. I was nominated for a Pulitzer.
我在西班牙服役 还认识海明威
I fought in Spain, and I know Ernest Hemingway.
- 我真的认识他 - 胡说
- I actually... I know him. - Oh, bullshit.
他也认识我
And he knows me.
假如在巴黎的酒吧遇见他
If I walked into a bar in Paris, he...
他可能不记得我名字
Maybe not my name, but he'll...
但至少会招手
I'll get a wave.
希望如此
Yeah.
你得过该死的国家图书奖
You... You won the National fucking Book Award.
但现在我们在做什么？
I mean, what are we doing?
回到正题
Okay, so the alien...
外星人让农庄女怀孕了
The alien impregnates the farm girl.
- 没错 - 为什么？
- Right. - Why?
因为他想播种并繁殖新的物种
Because he wants to inseminate her and propagate a new species
- 然后占领地球？ - 不
- on Earth and take over? - No.
因为她让他想起家乡的女孩
Because she reminds him of the girl he left behind.
但他头这么大
But he's got a bug head.
他家乡的女孩 头一定也很大
His girlfriend's probably got a bug head back home.
人不会迷恋外表
You don't get hung up on the looks of someone.
他爱上了她
He's falling in love with her.
好吧
Uh, okay.
你想太多了
You're over-thinking.
- 你还好吗？ - 还好
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
要不要休息一下？
You want to do this later?
不 请继续
No. Go, please.
好吧
All right.
难道你不怀念过去的时光？
I mean, do you ever miss writing something...
不说是伟大 但至少是好作品
Forget great, just good?
你脑中一定有很多好点子 是吧？
I mean, you must have ideas still, right?
有几个
I've got a few.
其中有一个萦绕不去
There's one that won't go away.
好几年前 克莉欧和我在墨西哥看斗牛
Cleo and I are in Mexico at a bullfight years ago.
那只牛死了
And the bull dies.
成千上万的观众却在欢呼
And, uh, thousands of people are just cheering.
除了三个人
Three weren't.
克莉欧 我 我们前面的一个小男孩
Cleo, me and this young boy down front,
他哭了
crying.
我一直好奇他哭的原因
Always wondered why.
等你找到答案后 就会写出来了
Well, (COUGHS) you write it and you'll know.
答应我 别交给该死的法兰克金
But please promise me, not for Frank fucking King.
拜托
Please.
颁发最佳编剧奖的演员也热爱阅读
To present the writing awards, here is an actor who also reads.
1954年3月
欢迎柯克·道格拉斯
Mr. Kirk Douglas.
妮琪 快点
Niki, hurry!
是谁颁奖？
Who's doing it?
来了来了
I'm coming, I'm coming!
信封
The envelope.
奥斯卡得主是
And the Oscar goes to
《罗马假日》编剧 伊恩·麦克连·汉特
Roman Holiday by Ian McLellan Hunter. (GASPS)
万岁 爸 你得奖了
Yes! That's you, Dad, that's you!
爸 太棒了
Dad, that is fantastic!
我代表伊恩·麦克连·汉特领奖
This is accepted on behalf of Ian McLellan Hunter.
我们可以过幸福快乐的生活了吗？
So do we get to be happy now?
我不想要
I don't want it.
我也不想要
Well, I don't want it.
上面写了你的名字
Your name's on it.
但剧本是你写的
You wrote it.
他们把奖给了你
They gave it to you.
它让我创造了奇迹
And it's done me wonders.
这是轰动世界的剧本
Here's the gorilla script.
- 爸 - 在
- Hey, Dad. - Ah?
有你的电话
Phone for you.
找哪个名字？
For which name?
找你 一个叫巴迪·罗斯的人打来的
No, you. Some guy named Buddy Ross.
看来传言是真的？《罗马假日》是你写的？
So, is the rumor true? You wrote Roman Holiday?
我能帮上什么忙吗 巴迪？
What can I do for you, Buddy?
电影票房失利 让我坠入万丈深渊
My movies have all bombed. Dug me into a hole.
终于要拍一部
I finally got something going.
超级大片
Classy.
我找来三位巨星 但剧本…
Three big stars. The script...
别提了 根本没剧本
What script? There is no script.
我找了11个作家都写不好 演员即将退出
I got 11 writers who fucked me and now the actors are gonna pull out.
若真如此 我将失去一切
And if they do, I lose everything.
你何时要拍？
When do you shoot?
十天后
Ten days.
有任何参考资料吗？
Is there anything?
当然 我无法让你署名
There'd be no credit, obviously.
开拍后才能支付酬劳
I can't pay you till we start shooting.
要是你唾弃我 我不会怪你
I wouldn't blame you if you spit in my face.
但我们曾经合作过好作品
But we did good stuff back then.
真的
We really did.
拜托你
Please.
我还要帮金氏兄弟改写一部剧本
I owe the King Brothers a rewrite.
无法两者兼顾
And I can't do both.
剧本在这里 我需要你帮忙接手
Here it is. I need you to take over.
好让你帮助伟大的巴迪·罗斯
So you can help that great guy, Buddy Ross.
这样我们才能继续消灭那张黑名单
So we can keep tearing down the blacklist.
天啊 又来了
Oh, Jesus, here we go.
如果巴迪拿到好剧本 会是部卖座大片
This is going to be a very big movie, and if Buddy gets a good script...
剧本是你给他的
Which you're gonna give him.
我是卖给他
No, which I am going to sell him.
为了赚钱 这就是我们写剧本的目的
For money, 'cause that's why we did all of this, right?
就为了钱
Was for the money.
你怎么看不清这点？
Why can you not see this?
拍出卖座片 我们就能继续接拍大片
If we get one big movie, we can get all the big movies.
讽刺地终结这腐败的一切
And then this whole rotten thing could collapse on the sheer irony
所有被封杀的剧作家都活跃得很
that every unemployable writer is employed.
天哪 你一定要讲得这么
Jesus Christ, do you have to say everything
冠冕堂皇吗？
like it's going to be chiseled into a rock?
我不会帮你协助巴迪·罗斯
I'm not gonna help you help Buddy Ross!
天啊
God's sake!
- 你总是要拒绝我的好点子 - 不 我…
- You are against every... - No, I...
让我们有所作为吧
solid idea that comes up. Let's do something!
那些混蛋做了伤天害理的事
These fuckers did things!
我们应该把他们告到一败涂地
We should be suing that cockroach into the ground
- 包括那些议员 - 好主意
- along with those congressmen... - There's an idea.
- 还有制作人 - 太棒了
- Yes, and the producers! - Very good one.
- 还有片厂 - 这样更好
- Yes, and the studios! - That'll be better.
- 我们应该告上法庭 - 很好
- We should sue them! - Oh, yes, brilliant!
继续打败仗 把钱都送给律师
Keep losing. Give all of your money away to lawyers!
我情愿为正义而败
I'd rather lose for the right reasons.
为什么？
Why?
失败就是失败
It's still losing.
你输 我输 大家都输
You lose. I lose. We all lose!
你看不出来吗？
Don't you see that?
国家依然噤若寒蝉 死气沉沉
And the whole goddamn country stays scared and dead.
你真以为可以这样过一辈子吗？
Well, you really think you can go on living like this forever?
我是过不完了
Well, I'm not gonna have to.
亚伦 我们办得到的
Arlen, we can do this.
我们能打败他们 我们能赢
We can beat them. We can win!
- 我不在乎输赢 - 胡说
- I don't care if I win. - Bullshit!
每个人都想赢
Everybody wants to win.
不 你想赢 我想改变世界
No, you want to win. I want to change things.
- 只要赢了就能改变世界 - 才怪
- I want to win so that I can change things. - No you don't!
你只想赢得一座标着你名字的奥斯卡奖
You want to win so that you can get an Oscar with your name on it this time.
这样就能赚更多钱来 为那些白痴写一堆烂戏
And so you can get more money that you burn through, writing shit for idiots!
你真幼稚 我得把什么都解释清楚吗
Why do I have to explain everything to you like you're a fucking child?
不必解释
You don't have to.
- 你真的不必解释 - 滚吧
- You really don't have to. - Piss off!
你想做什么都可以
You know, you do what you do and that's fine for you.
但别假装你重振事业之后
But don't pretend that you getting your career back
就能拯救全人类 好吗？
is part of some great crusade for mankind. Okay?
我这么做是为了大家
I'm doing this for everyone.
亚伦
Arlen...
愚不可及
Fucking idiot.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快乐 亲爱的妮可拉
Happy birthday, dear Nikola
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you
许个愿
Make a wish.
我拍到了
I got it.
甜蜜16岁
Sweet 16!
靠你妹妹近一点
Get together with your sister.
克里斯 一起来
Chris, get in there.
谢谢
Ah. Thank you.
我们真不用去敲爸爸的门？
Are you sure we shouldn't go knock?
不用
I'm sure.
他连五分钟都抽不出来？
He can't take five minutes?
是啊
Nope.
二分钟呢？
Two minutes?
妮可
Niki.
一分钟就好
One minute.
克里斯 拿个好点的盘子 谢谢
Chris, would you please get the good plates?
- 好的 妈妈 - 谢谢
- Yes, Mom. - Thank you.
爸
Dad!
- 爸 - 走开
- Dad! - Go away!
我们在吃生日蛋糕
We're having birthday cake.
如果你听到我在工作 就别敲门
When you hear me working, you don't knock!
但这是我的生日
But it's my birthday.
别敲门 千万不要
You don't knock! Ever!
就算房子着火 你也不想知道？
So the house is on fire, you don't want to know?
我在澡盆里 泡着水呢
I work in a bathtub, surrounded by water.
我敢说就算全国都失火
So I'm fairly certain that even if the whole goddamn country was on fire,
我还是能继续为这个家做牛做马
that I could still function as this family's personal slave.
我只求不受打扰
And all I ask is to not be interrupted
去你的 只不过是切个生日蛋糕
for every little slice of fucking birthday cake!
怎样？太荒谬了
What? It's ridiculous!
我不知道进行到哪里了 天啊
Now I've lost my place. Christ's sake!
或许你能如愿活得长长久久
sure, maybe you, uh,
get that long, happy life we all want.
但你将永远无法安心入眠
But your eyes never really close again.
你会一辈子害怕夜里发出的声响
'Cause you spend that life
scared of every noise in the dark.
我们都将如此 我不能害你变成这样
We both do. I can't let you do this, Rocco.
因此我必须说服你
I'll just have to convince you I'm right.
毕竟这就是朋友该做的事
After all, kid, what are friends for?
别帮他说话
Don't defend him, okay?
他知道自己错了
He knows he's wrong.
但他完全没道歉
He hasn't even apologized.
我觉得你让他大吃一惊
I think you surprised him.
他不习惯家里还有其他大人在
He's not used to seeing another adult in the house.
他总是对的
He has to be right all the time.
你怎么能受得了？
How do you stand it?
有时确实难以忍受 尤其是最近
Well, it's challenging sometimes, especially lately.
不如跟我一起去躺楼下
Hey, why don't you come downstairs with me?
我想给你看一样东西
I wanna show you something.
有看见我的手套吗？
You see my gloves?
谢谢
Thank you.
你拿这当他的头来打吗？
Do you imagine that's his head?
不 但你可以
No. But you can.
妮可 剧本好了吗？
Niki, is that the script already?
太棒了
Fantastic.
跟你爸说…
Ah. Tell your dad that...
你好 我找亚伦·赫德
Oh, hello. Um, I'm looking for Arlen Hird.
特朗勃先生 我是安德鲁
Mr. Trumbo, it's Andrew.
天啊 你长这么大了
Good God! Look... Look at you!
我想你爸
Wow. Well, I'm certain your father
一定说过我的坏话
has told you some nasty things about me,
我跟你保证
but I want to assure you,
他说的都是真的
they're all true.
他在家吗？
Is, uh... Is he home?
抱歉 我以为你有听到消息
I'm sorry. I thought you knew.
- 真遗憾 - 非常感谢
- I'm so sorry. - Thank you so much.
安德鲁
Andrew.
约书亚
Joshua.
爸爸留了一样东西给你
My dad left something for you.
是份记录
It's a record.
记了他欠你和其他人的钱
Money that he owed you and some other people.
抱歉 我也希望能把钱还清
I'm sorry. I wish we could pay you back.
别这么说 安德鲁
Andrew, no.
是我欠他的
I owed him.
这些都是我欠的债
The debts are all mine.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好 艾迪
Hello, Eddie.
没想到你会来找我
This is a bit of a surprise.
有什么事吗？
What can I do for you?
亚伦死了
Arlen died.
我在外景拍戏时听说了
I heard. I was on location.
这是你当初捐给辩护基金的钱
This is the money you gave us for the defense fund.
我们欠你的 包括亚伦在内
It's everything that we owe you. Arlen included.
不 我不打算要回来
No, now, that was a gift.
但我们希望把账结清
We'd like it off our books.
什么意思？你话中有话
What is this supposed to be? Some kind of message?
你 亚伦和好莱坞十君子都瞧不起我
What you and Arlen and the great Hollywood Ten all think of me.
好吧 但请听我解释
Fine. Fine. But first you're gonna listen.
在你坐牢之后
After you went to jail,
我一整年都没有工作
I didn't work for a year.
没有戏约 连试演都没有
No offers, not even an audition.
人人都与我保持距离
People would see me, cross the street.
那些我爱的人
People I loved.
以及靠我发大财的人
People I made rich.
我被传唤至委员会
I sat in front of that committee.
可是为什么 我可什么也没做
Why? I didn't do anything.
我们什么都没做 只是不懂事的小娃儿
None of us did anything. We were all stupid babies.
没做任何不法勾当
With no business in any of it.
我只想回到原本的生活
I just wanted my life back.
他们掌握了每一个名字 包括你和亚伦
They had every name. Yours, Arlen's, everybody's.
我提供的资讯 他们早就有了
I didn't give them anything they didn't already have.
我终结了这一切 仅此而已
I ended it, is all. I just... I ended it!
艾迪 提供他们无权过问的资讯
Oh, Eddie, you don't end something like this.
没办法终结任何事情
By giving them what they have no right to ask.
你要教我该怎么做吗？
You're gonna tell me how I should have handled it?
像你对付议会那样？
Like you handled Congress?
难道你以这件事情为荣吗？
So you're saying that you're proud of what you did?
谁有资格感到荣耀？
Proud? Who the hell gets to be proud?
只有你
You. You do.
使用那些假名和掩护
You with your fake names and your fronts.
成功重返编剧事业
You've got all the work you want.
而我却必须每天亲身面对世界
I gotta go out in the world every day.
这是我的工作
This is my work.
我没办法化身为另一个人
I've got nobody else to be.
我当时别无选择
I did what I had to.
你做得心甘情愿 艾迪
You did what you wanted, Eddie.
为了获得更大的成功
And you did it for more.
接拍更多电影 赚更多钱
More movies, more money,
买更多死人画的烂东西挂在墙上
more dead bullshit on your walls.
我的事我自己承担 但你害亚伦
What I did, I did, but did you ever wonder how many years
少活了多少年
you hacked off Arlen's life?
只为了昭告天下 自己是个叛逆天才？
To show the world what a rebel genius you are.
你必须承担这个责任
You live with that!
一个人喝吗？
Drinking alone?
我愿意
Preferably.
你最近都在忙什么？
And what are you up to these days?
赫达 也许再喝一杯我就会告诉你
You know, Hedda, another one of these and I just may tell you.
那我请你
Oh, then I'm buying.
一样的再来一杯
Usual. Same again.
是 霍珀小姐
Yes, Miss Hopper.
拜托 我听见谣言了
Oh, come on, I hear the rumors.
告诉我 你仍在战场上英勇奋战
Show me you're still in the game, fighting the good fight.
快来打我的脸
Come on, rub my face in it.
告诉我你在偷偷写哪一部片
Whisper a movie you've written in secret.
或许我已经听说过了
Maybe I've even heard of it.
或许吧
Maybe you have.
抱歉 拍片忙坏我了
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry... I'm filming. It's crazy.
巴迪 你认识达尔顿·特朗勃吗？
Buddy, do you know Dalton Trumbo?
认识 我们以前曾经合作过
Yes, I believe we have worked together before.
是在米高梅吗？好几百年前的事了
What was it? Was it MGM?
很高兴再次见到你 巴迪
A million years ago. Nice to see you again, Buddy.
听说你的新剧本难产
I hear your new script's in trouble.
或许你该雇用他
Maybe you should hire Dalton.
他以前写得很好但很贵 现在应该会便宜点
He used to be pretty good, and price-wise, he'd be bargain basement.
你以前不愿意 但巴迪把你供出来了
Not that you'd ever do it. Not after Buddy named names.
你不知道吗？
Oh, you didn't know?
谣传他雇用了一个不该雇的人
Word was he had hired someone he shouldn't have.
所以他被传唤出庭作证
So he got subpoenaed. He had to testify.
过程不公开 没上新闻 这样能容易点
Closed session. No press. Makes it easier.
所以他当然就把你供出来了
So, he named you, of course.
现在他已恢复清白 继续拍片
Now he's been cleared. Gets to make his movie.
一切都要感谢你
In a way, thanks to you.
要喝一杯吗？你看起来需要酒精
Drink, Buddy? You look as if you need one.
你相信吗？民主党竟然赞成种族隔离
Democrats voting for segregation.
保守的南方民主党人
Oh, the Southern Dixie-crats.
我们已开始联名上书消除种族差别待遇
We started a petition for total integration.
联名书在这里
There it is.
已有超过一千人签名
I already have over 1,000 signatures.
那我很乐意当第一千零一个
Well, I'd be happy to make it 1,001.
这是新的剧本
And this is the new draft
要送去阿古拉山给海米金
that needs to be delivered to Hymie King in Agoura.
阿古拉山？我以为金氏兄弟在好莱坞
Wait, Agoura? I thought the Kings were in Hollywood.
不 这是改过的剧本
Oh, no, no, no. These are the rewrites.
今晚就要拍 必须立刻送到拍摄现场
They're to be shot tonight, so Hymie needs them on the set right away.
阿古拉山距离60几公里
Agoura's 40 miles.
是的 克里斯现在知道了
Yes, I'm sure Chris knows that by now.
他去不了
Well, he can't.
什么？
I'm sorry?
他有约会 要带女生去看电影
He has a date. He's taking her to a movie.
那么 妮可拉 就由你送去
Well, all right, then, Nikola, you'll deliver the draft.
我要示威
I have a protest.
示威游行需要准时开始？
Since when do protests have hard start times?
我送去吧
I'll take it.
妮可拉会送
Nikola will take it.
我说了我不行
I said I can't.
小姐 你必须送去
Young lady, you will.
这很重要
This is important.
这也很重要
So is this.
这对我而言很重要
This is important to me.
约会对他而言很重要 你想别的办法
And the date's important to Chris, so figure something else out.
动作快点 人家马上就要
Move on! He needs those now!
亲爱的
Oh, honey...
她离家不算太久 现在也不算太晚
She hasn't been gone that long, and it's really not that late.
显然她是故意要让我们担心
You know, this is a blatant attempt to manipulate worry.
你知道我何时决定离开哈尔的吗？
Do you know when I realized that I had to leave Hal?
哈尔是谁？
Hal? Hal who?
我的第一任丈夫
My first husband Hal.
我的老天爷啊
Jesus, take the wheel!
就在婚礼当晚
It was my wedding night.
我第一次结婚那天
My first wedding night with Hal.
如果你一定要谈不愉快的陈年旧事
If we're going to go back in time
to that unholy coupling,
那我得喝一杯才能撑下去
then I have a medical obligation to drink.
我觉得没办法跟他一起养育孩子
I saw this was not a man I could have children with.
感谢老天
Now, thank God for that.
他会欺凌我和孩子们
He'd bully me and them.
我们一家将永远过着不幸的日子
And that we'd wind up like
every miserable family since forever.
但是你不同
But you...
我以为你永远不会变成那样
I knew you would never be like that.
不论外界多少风雨
That whatever happened out there,
你真正最重视的
all that would matter,
一定是家人
really matter, was us.
当然 我最重视家人
Well, all that matters is us.
不
No.
你变了
Not anymore.
你不明白自己可能失去什么
You have no idea what you could lose.
拜托
Oh, please!
我的事业
My career
宪法第一修正案 这个国家
and the First Amendment, our country.
还有什么
Am I missing anything?
我们一家人
Us.
你会失去我们
You're losing us. Oh.
从监狱回来后你不说话 不关心问候
Since prison, you don't talk or ask.
只会愤怒咆啸
You just snap and bark.
我一直在等你用木槌敲打餐桌
I keep waiting for you to start pounding the dinner table with a gavel.
原来在被世界贱弃之余
So in addition to being a pariah out in the world,
我还得对抗
I also have the supreme joy of battling insurrection
- 自己家里的暴动 - 暴动？
- in my own home where these... - Battling insurrection?
而我每个手指都在努力让家人温饱
ten fingers literally clothe and feed and shelter us.
苦难的不只是你
This isn't just happening to you!
我们都受到了伤害
We all hurt!
妮可 我 还有你的朋友
Niki, me, your friends!
朋友？哪来的朋友？
Friends? What friends?
谁还有闲情逸致交朋友？
Who the hell has the luxury of friends?
我身边不是盟军就是敌人
I've got allies and enemies.
容不下别人了
There's no room for anything else.
我们都知道
We know.
很好
Good.
讨论结束
Then this discussion ends.
这不是讨论 我在向你宣战
This isn't a discussion. It's a fight.
我不会把孩子让恶霸教养
I will not let our children be raised by a bully.
马上回来
Be back.
好的
All right.
我不想在朋友面前和你吵架 但我不打算回家
I didn't want to fight in front of my friends, but I'm not going home.
我不是来跟你吵架的
I didn't come here to fight.
你母亲不是个多话的人
You know, your mother is a quiet person.
一般而言是如此
Normally.
因此
The effect of which is that
她总能让我听见自己的声音
she can actually make me hear myself.
真了不起
It's extraordinary.
我不是很喜欢最近的自己
Lately, it's not a sound I like much.
主要是因为我的声音
Mostly because what I hear is just how...
透露出我有多么恐惧
How afraid I am.
怕伤害了你
Afraid that I'm scarring you...
和其他家人
All of you.
要是最后我们输光一切 该怎么办？
And what if it's all for nothing? What then?
所以我挺身而战
Well, so, I fight.
否则我也不知道该怎么办
It's all I know how to do anymore.
任何碍事的人
Any... I mean, it's just...
都会让我大发雷霆
Just rage at anyone who gets in my way.
但我从不觉得你碍事
But you have never been in my way, Nikola.
一次也没有
Not once.
真不敢相信我竟会对你如此生气
It's crazy how mad you make me.
我一直想变得像你一样
Since all I ever wanted was to be just like you.
恐怕你已经成功了
Well, I'm afraid to say that you've succeeded.
我们已经知道了
We know, okay?
世界很小 谣言不会空穴来风
It's a small town. The gossip's always true.
你必须解雇道顿·特朗勃一干人等
Fire Dalton Trumbo and the rest of them
否则你将面临抗议 新闻报料 抵制
or you got pickets, headlines and boycotts.
我们会把你逐出电影界
We will put you right out of business.
"我们"？
We?
守护美国理想电影联盟
The Motion Picture Alliance for the Preservation of American Ideals.
包括我 罗纳德·里根 赫达·霍珀
Me and Ronald Reagan, Hedda Hopper,
公会 片厂老板 以及约翰·韦恩
guilds, studio heads, John Wayne.
我喜欢约翰·韦恩
I love John Wayne.
我会介绍给你认识
Well, I'll introduce you.
你们可以一起拍片
You guys could do a movie together.
太棒了
Oh, gee, that would be swell.
可惜我们
Except I don't think
- 当不成朋友 - 嘿 法兰克
- you and me are gonna be pals. - Hey, Frank!
- 你不让我雇用工会的人？- 法兰克 法兰克
- You wanna keep me from hiring union? - Frank! Frank!
我就去闹区找酒鬼和妓女
I'll go downtown, hire a bunch of winos and hookers!
我才不在乎
It doesn't matter!
- 我专拍垃圾片 - 法兰克！
- I make garbage! - Frank!
想在报纸上称我为赤色分子？随你便
You want to call me a pinko in the papers? Do it!
看我电影的人根本不识字
None of the people that go to my fucking movies can read! No, wait.
我拍片为的是钱和女人 要多少有多少
I am in this for the money and the pussy and they're both falling off the trees.
想拿就拿去
Take it away from me.
我不会告你
Go ahead. I won't sue you,
但这会是你被我打死前
but this will be the last fucking thing you see
看见的最后画面
before I beat you to death with it.
蒂芬妮 送客
Tiffany!
来了
Right here.
你来干嘛？
Fuck you want?
- 我写了新剧本 - 是吗？
- New script. - Oh, yeah?
是一出家庭剧
Yes, it's a family picture.
这个故事一直放在我心里
Something I've been mulling.
关于一个墨西哥男孩与他养的牛
It's the story of a young Mexican boy and his pet bull.
听起来不太卖钱 片名叫什么？
Sounds a little fruity. What's it called?
《勇敢的人》 但有一个问题
The Brave One. Oh, one problem though.
成本高吗？
Expensive?
烂问题
Worse.
这是个好剧本
It's good.
《勇敢的人》
谁告诉你的？他们还说了什么？
Who told you? What else did they say?
1957年1月
你也是 谢谢 法兰克
You too. And thank you, Frank.
怎么了？
What?
《勇敢的人》入围了奥斯卡
The Brave One has been nominated for an Academy Award.
- 真的吗？- 真的
- Really? - Yes, really!
太疯狂了
That's crazy.
不就和《罗马假日》当时一样？
I don't know. It's like Roman Holiday.
海米 和《罗马假日》天差地别
Oh, Hymie, this is nothing like Roman Holiday.
《罗马假日》的挂名编剧真有其人
Roman Holiday had a guy with a name and a body
他们还可以发奖
they could give the award to.
但劳勃瑞奇是捏造的名字 谁去领奖？
There is no Robert Rich. Who gets the thing if it wins?
或许不会得奖
Well, maybe it won't.
这部片又没多好 无意冒犯
I mean, it's not that good. No offense.
我不介意
None taken.
欢迎电影界最美丽的
And now I'd like to say two of the most beautiful words
1957年3月
黛博拉·蔻儿
in the motion-picture industry, Deborah Kerr.
奥斯卡最佳编剧入围的有
The nominations for Best Motion Picture Story are,
劳勃·瑞奇的《勇敢的人》
Robert Rich for The Brave One,
李奥·凯驰的《艾迪杜钦传》
Leo Katcher for The Eddy Duchin Story,
尚·保罗·沙特的《奇异的爱情》
Jean-Paul Sartre for The Proud and the Beautiful,
以及塞沙尔·萨瓦提尼的《风烛泪》
and Cesare Zavattini for Umberto D.
请把信封给我
The envelope please.
得奖的是《勇敢的人》劳勃·瑞奇
The Brave One, Robert Rich!
爸！
Dad!
他是谁？
You won! Who's that guy?
由编剧工会副主席
Mr. Jesse Lasky Jr., Vice President of the screenwriter's branch
杰斯·拉斯基二世 代为领奖
of the Writers Guild, will accept the award for Mr. Rich.
我代劳勃·瑞奇与他的优美故事
On behalf of Robert Rich and his beautiful story,
谢谢各位
thank you very much.
真诡异
So weird.
我到处找不到瑞奇先生 显然他…
We can't find Mr. Rich anywhere. He apparently...
劳勃·瑞奇究竟是何方神圣？
Who the hell is Robert Rich?
我得挂了
I gotta go.
最好不要是谣传的那个人
It had better not be who they say.
特朗勃先生
Mr. Trumbo. Yes?
你就是劳勃·瑞奇？
Are you Robert Rich?
《勇敢的人》是不是你的作品？
Did you write The Brave One?
我一向不作声称
Well, you see, it's my policy
自己参与过任何电影
not to claim credit for any one movie.
不然每部电影岂不是都有我的份
That way, it's possible that I had something to do with all of them.
当然烂片除外
Except the stinkers, which were all written
那都是我的敌人们写的
by my enemies.
你在黑名单属于哪个位置？
What's your position on the blacklist?
我就在黑名单上
Well, on it.
跟另外数千人列在一起
Along with thousands of others.
你是否试图以劳勃·瑞奇的争议终结黑名单？
Are you using this Robert Rich controversy to try and end it?
《勇敢的人》是部好片
See, The Brave One is a nice little picture.
如果谣传我有参与该片能帮助票房
And if rumors of my involvement
我欣然接受
can help sell tickets, well, then, good.
如果这种作者不明的怪事
And if the strange circumstances
能激起讨论
of its authorship raised a few questions,
那就更好了
well, even better.
- 特朗勃 - 是
- Trumbo? - Yes?
- 有人来电找你 - 是谁？
- Phone for you. - Well, who is it?
自称寇克·道格拉斯的疯子
Some crazy guy, says he's Kirk Douglas.
真的？谢谢你 妮可拉
Really? Huh. Well, thank you, Nikola.
你是妮可？我是寇克
Niki? Kirk.
寇克
Kirk.
达顿
Dalton.
抱歉
My apologies.
最近有太多恶作剧电话
We've had more than our share of crank calls lately.
- 我能想像 - 请坐
- I can imagine. - Please have a seat.
想喝什么？
May I get you a drink?
不必了 谢谢
No. No thank you.
好的
All right.
- 所以？- 我接了一支新片
- So? - I'm doing a new picture.
刚刚收到剧本
And I just got the script.
看来是长达七小时的娱乐大片
That must be seven hours of entertainment there.
可是没有一页有趣
Not a single page is entertaining.
但里头有个动人故事
But there's a good story in there somewhere.
关于一个试图对抗全世界的男人
About one man who tried to take on the whole world.
这有点意思
Well, you've got me so far.
身为奴隶的他 起义反抗罗马帝国
He was a slave who led a revolt against the Roman Empire.
片名叫什么？
Now, what's the title?
《斯巴达克斯》
Spartacus.
不不不
No, no, no.
我不能说自己正在写什么
I can't tell you what I'm working on now, except to say that
只能说 既然有黑名单 就有黑市
the blacklist is alive and well and so is the black market.
是的 你可以引用这段话
Well, yes, you can quote me on that.
看见我的名字上报 会让一些人抓狂
Seeing my name in the papers drives certain people out of their minds.
他来了
Of course. Here he is.
- 你好 寇克 - 你好 赫达
- Kirk. - Hedda.
他是我朋友 鲍伯·史崔普林
I'd like you to meet a friend of mine, Bob Stripling.
来自非美活动调查委员会
House Un-American Activities Committee.
道格拉斯先生 你好
Mr. Douglas.
史崔普林先生 你好
Mr. Stripling.
喝点东西吗
Drink?
不了 谢谢
No, thank you.
你有要事找我？
You said it was important.
只要你雇用了达尔顿·特朗勃
Only if you hired Dalton Trumbo.
我雇谁是我的事
Who I hire is my business.
不 道格拉斯先生
No, Mr. Douglas.
这关我们的事
It's ours.
为什么
Why?
因为我们要维护美国的安全
'Cause we have to keep this country safe.
怎么维护？
And how are you doing that?
要不请你上证人席看看吧
Well, why don't I show you by putting you on the stand?
赫达 你朋友打算恐吓我？
Hedda, is your friend trying to scare me?
他只是想让你知道 该怎么做事
He's just trying to show you the way things are.
或许我不喜欢这样做事
Maybe I don't like the way things are.
寇克 我们认识多年
Kirk, we've known each other a long time.
你什么时候变成了一个混帐？
Since when did you become such a bastard?
我一直都是个混帐 只是你没发现
I was always a bastard. You just never noticed.
1958年12月
什么事？
Yes?
我想见这部戏的编剧
I wish to see the man who wrote this.
请进
Please, come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是奥图·普莱明杰
I am Otto Preminger.
我是个导演
The director.
抱歉
Forgive me, I...
我几个小时前才刚忙完
I've just finished work a few hours ago. I...
我读完了你的剧本
A copy of which I've read.
怎么可能？
But how could...
我今天早上才寄出的
I just had that delivered this morning.
我是奥图·普莱明杰 我是导演
I am Otto Preminger, the director.
请进
Please.
我最小的孩子认为
Oh, yes, my youngest thinks
养鸟可以纾压
that I can end the suffering of all broken birds.
我都是吃烤鸟纾压
As can I, with a broiler.
寇克·道格拉斯委托你的剧本 写完了吗？
Are your duties completed for Mr. Kirk Douglas?
不 但我有两周的圣诞假期
No, but I do have two weeks off for Christmas.
这段期间你要跟我一起工作
During which time you will work with me.
是吗？
Will I?
如果你跟你的剧本一样聪明
If you're as intelligent as your writing.
并且与你的名声一样贪婪
And as greedy as your reputation.
我们要改编小说《出埃及记》
It is an adaptation of the novel Exodus.
你读过吗？
You've read it?
没有
No.
是本超级畅销书
A colossal bestseller.
几乎难看得要死
Very nearly a perfect piece of shit.
但里头有个好故事
But there's a good story in there somewhere.
我没概念
I have no idea.
但我找来了保罗·纽曼
But I have Paul Newman.
我们谈过了 他有点谨慎
We have spoken. He is a little reticent,
但价钱谈拢 他就会接受
but I believe, at the right price, he will accept.
你要接吗？
So you're doing it?
这是唯一能赶走他的方法
Well, I think it's the only way to get him to leave.
这很要紧
It's very important.
可怜的普莱明杰先生
Poor Mr. Preminger.
他以为他是猫 而你才是老鼠
He thinks he's the cat and you're the mouse.
《出埃及记》
瞧瞧 太棒了
Oh, look at that. Perfect.
梅兹那是什么？俄罗斯娃娃？
Hey, Mitzi, what's that? A Russian doll?
这是什么 圣诞老人？
Oh! What is this, Santa?
献给圣诞婆婆的小心意
Just a little something for Mrs. Claus.
我等等再拆
I'll open it later.
圣诞节结束了
Christmas is over.
好吧
Well...
你读了最新写的那几场戏？
Did you read the new scenes?
糟透了 继续保持这种水准
Dreadful. Keep up this level of work,
你的名字就会在我的电影里出现
and I will see to it your name is on my movie.
以承受骂名
To take the blame.
好了 拿去
Well, there you go.
你好 山米
Ooh! Hello. Hi, Sammy.
你知道它是寇克·道格拉斯送的吗？
Oh, do you know that Kirk Douglas gave me this bird?
它会害你分心
It's a distraction.
完全不会
No. No, not at all.
我给它取名为山姆·杰克森
I named him Sam Jackson.
《斯巴达克斯》就是他写的
He wrote Spartacus.
如何？
Well?
- 有进步 - 感谢老天
- Better. - Thank God.
但还不是天才之作
But it simply lacks genius.
奥图 如果每场戏都很精彩
Otto, if every scene is brilliant,
你的电影会变得单调乏味
your movie is going to be utterly monotonous.
我告诉你
I'll tell you what.
你把每一场戏写得精彩无比
You write every scene brilliantly,
而我会导得高潮迭起
and I will direct unevenly.
什么事 亲爱的？
What is it, dear?
谢谢
Thank you.
哈啰 寇克
Oh, hello, Kirk.
圣诞快乐 谢谢你 梅兹
Merry Christmas. Thank you, Mitzi.
奥图 你好吗？
Otto. How are you?
我很好 寇克
I am very well, Kirk.
我无意打断你们
I, uh, didn't mean to interrupt.
不 没这回事
No, no. No, not at all. Not at all.
奥图 请让我们谈谈
Otto, would you mind if we had a little chat?
一会儿就好
Won't be a second.
我还以为撞见了自己的老婆
I sort of feel like I walked in on my wife.
你喜欢他吗？
Do you love him?
可怕极了
Oh, it's far more lurid than that.
他竟然付费买我的服务
He's paying me for my services.
我也是
So am I.
按约定 我会在1月2日向你交稿
And you'll get them again, January 2nd, as promised.
我只需要你拨冗几天 写几场新戏
I just need you a few days on some of the new scenes.
当然 但要等2号以后
Of course, but not until the 2nd.
我也不想这样 但我没遇过
I wouldn't ask, but I've never had a director
比库伯·力克更令人头痛的导演
who's a bigger pain in my ass than Stanley Kubrick.
最糟的是 他是对的
The worst part is, he's right.
我不想拒绝你 但…
Well, I wouldn't refuse, but...
这是我们之间的秘密
Well, I really... This should remain between us.
当然
Of course.
普莱明杰宣称
Preminger has declared that...
他说
Well, what he said was,
"继续保持这种水准"
"You keep up this level of work,
"你的名字就会在我的电影里出现"
"and I'll see to it that your name is on my movie."
- 真的吗？ - 没错
- Really? - Oh, yes.
一字不假
Those were his exact words.
保持联系
Be in touch.
很好
Very well.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
你也是
You too.
我猜他想要你回去
I suppose he wants you back.
不
Well, no. No, no. He...
他来串门 顺便讨论演职人员名单
He just stopped by to talk about a screen credit.
《斯巴达克斯》的名单？
On Spartacus?
我不能透露任何细节
Well, I really shouldn't have said anything.
你懂的
You understand.
休息五分钟 大家五分钟后回来
Five minutes! Back in five minutes, everybody!
寇克
Kirk,
赫达·霍珀说 如果你不解雇特朗勃
Hedda Hopper just told me the American Legion is going to boycott us
退伍军人协会将发动抵制活动
unless you get rid of Trumbo.
艾德 本片剧本与他无关
Ed, he's not done with the script.
片中没有他的名字
His name will never be on the thing.
有什么好抵制的？
What's anybody boycotting?
寇克 不好意思
Kirk... Just a second. Please. Please.
请让我们独处一会儿
Just give me five seconds, please.
二千万美国人明确表示
Listen. Twenty million Americans are saying loud and clear,
你不解雇一位编剧 他们就不买票
they will never buy a ticket to our movie unless you fire one writer.
这里有50人 选一个吧
Here's 50! Pick one.
我可以插句话吗？
Mind if I stick my nose in?
请说
Please.
他知道内幕 他看见寇克·道格拉斯进出
He knows. He sees Kirk Douglas coming in and out of here.
以及奥图·普莱明杰和他的劳斯莱斯
And Otto Preminger and his Rolls.
他是个白痴 但他并不笨
He's an idiot. But he's not stupid.
他向联邦调查局告密了吗？
Has he called the FBI?
国会呢？
Congress?
没有 因为他们能给你的惩罚早就给了
No, because everything they can do, they've already done.
那座奥斯卡奖是属于你的
That Oscar belongs to you.
去拿回来吧
Get it!
天啊 你一点都不像我
My God! You're nothing like me.
你比我更可怕
You're worse.
请你正式声明 你是劳勃·瑞奇？
For the record, you're Robert Rich?
是的
I am.
我看过名单了
I've been through the whole list, Ed.
上面都是假名
They're all hacks.
《勇敢的人》是你写的？
And you wrote The Brave One?
没错
I did.
艾德 我等等回电给你
Ed, let me call you back.
为何你现在站出来？
Why come forward now?
我被非美活动调查委员会
Well, as someone who has been thoroughly investigated
彻底调查过
by the House Un-American Activities Committee,
我实在好奇 为何没人
I started wondering, why hasn't anyone taken
审查这个组织
a good long look at them
以及他们对电影产业造成的影响？
and their work in the movie industry?
该组织的宗旨是 揪出敌方特工
You see, they were convened to uncover enemy agents,
揭露共产阴谋 并制定反叛乱法
expose communist conspiracies and write anti-sedition laws.
但经过了数千小时
Well, here we are, thousands of hours
耗费了数百万元之后
and millions of dollars later.
没有任何特工被揪出
Agents uncovered, zero.
没有任何阴谋被揭露 没有任何法条被制定
Conspiracies exposed, zero. Laws written, zero.
他们所做的只是否定别人的工作权
You see, all they do is deny people their right to work.
我因此丧失权益
And they can't even get that right.
以及二座奥斯卡奖
Academy Awards, two.
你作何感想？
And how does that feel?
深深伤害你的黑名单 竟然只是个笑话
To have so undermined the blacklist that it's almost a joke.
笑话？
A joke?
这张创造出劳勃·瑞奇的黑名单
I know the blacklist that produced Robert Rich.
我见过它的可怕与残酷
I've seen its horror and cruelty.
它可憎地浪费我过去的人生
A hideous waste of life
我只能长年做个无名氏
as I've walked in the long line of its anonymous.
我无法再巧妙捏造出下个劳勃·瑞奇
And I cannot invent one more witticism about Robert Rich
或另一座无人能认领的奥斯卡奖
or the Oscar he can't claim.
因为那座小小的
Because that small,
毫无用处的小金人
worthless golden statue
上面沾满了我朋友们的鲜血
is covered with the blood of my friends.
我来接
I'll get it.
喂？你好 奥图
Hello? Oh, hello, Otto.
我读了你最新版的剧本
I've read your last draft.
你觉得如何？
What do you think?
纽约时报今天的头版 就是我的回应
My answer is on the front page of today's New York Times.
奥图·普莱明杰宣布 《出埃及记》由达尔顿·特朗勃编剧
你这么讨厌啊？
You hated it that much?
圣诞快乐 特朗勃先生
Merry Christmas, Mr. Trumbo.
艾德 请坐
Ed, have a seat.
- 为什么不杀了他？- 杀啊
- Well, why doesn't he kill him? - Kill him.
杀了他
Kill him!
- 快杀啊 你这个蠢货 - 杀了他
- Kill him, you imbecile! - Kill him!
杀…
Kill him!
很棒 很棒
Great. Great.
马蒂 播放薇瑞妮亚和克拉苏那一幕
Marty, have them put up the scene with Varinia and Crassus.
- 听我说 寇克 - 等一下
- Listen, Kirk, I... - One second.
华伦 我想请你发一则新闻稿
Warren, I'd like you to put out a press release.
该片…等等 华伦
The screen... One second, Warren.
想到斯巴达克斯 你会想起什么？
What do you remember when you think about Spartacus?
他像只动物般孤身起义
He was a man who began all alone like an animal.
但他死去那天 却有千千万万人
Yet on the day he died, thousands and thousands
愿意替他而死
would gladly have died in his place.
这算什么？他是神吗？
What was he? Was he a god?
他不是神
He wasn't a god.
他只是个男人 一个奴隶
He was simple man. A slave.
我爱过他
I loved him.
华伦 新闻稿这么写
Warren, the press release will say,
《斯巴达克斯》由达尔顿·特朗勃编剧
"The screenplay for Spartacus was written by Dalton Trumbo."
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你不解雇特朗勃 就由我来动手
Kirk, if you don't get rid of Trumbo, I will.
那等我离开后 你可以重拍我的戏份
And right after I quit, you can reshoot all my scenes.
艾德 再怎么样
You see, Ed, for better or worse,
我演的可是斯巴达克斯呢
I am Spartacus.
这部电影即将上映 名叫《斯巴达克斯》
There's a picture coming out. It's called Spartacus.
主演 寇克·道格拉斯
It's starring Kirk Douglas,
编剧 达尔顿·特朗勃
and it is written by Dalton Trumbo.
如果署名是别的编剧
If there is some other writer's name on it,
请勿相信
don't believe it.
他们已经被我们看穿了
We're on to them.
- 喂？ - 听好了 艾德
- Yes? - Now, listen, Ed.
我们会到所有放映的影院外抗议
We'll picket every theater that movie is in
除非你今晚撤片
unless you pull the prints tonight.
并将那个叛徒的名字抹掉
And you get that traitor's name off it.
赫达 别这么逼我
Hedda, you can't put me in this position.
既浪费钱又没意义
That's expensive and pointless.
那你和你的电影你的片厂 一起吃屎去吧
Then you can kiss your movie, your studio and your miserable ass goodbye.
环球影业斥资一千二百万的《斯巴达克斯》
Hollywood turns out in force to hail UI's new film spectacle, Spartacus,
首映会上许多好莱坞名人现身力挺
on the premier of the $12-million picture, in the film colony.
现场的抗议人士也向我们提示着
The protesters also showed up to remind everyone of the political controversy
本片制作期间引发的政治争议
surrounding the making of this film.
《斯巴达克斯》
执行制作 寇克·道格拉斯
编剧 达尔顿·特朗勃
克莉欧？
Cleo?
怎么了 发生什么事？
What is it? What's wrong?
一切都结束了 是吧？
It's over, isn't it?
是的 没错
Yes. Yes.
我们撑过来了
And we made it.
是的
Yes.
华盛顿特区 1961年2月
肯尼迪总统难得在晚上的私人时间
President Kennedy enjoyed a rare evening off
看了寇克·道格拉斯的新片《斯巴达克斯》
attending the new Kirk Douglas film, Spartacus.
记者正在现场 等候总统发言
We are here live, awaiting the president's comments.
总统先生
Mr. President, Mr. President, Mr. President!
对这部颇具争议的电影
It's a very controversial film.
您有何感想？
What did you think?
我认为拍得很好
Oh, I think it's a fine picture,
应该会大卖
and I think it's going to be a big hit.
肯尼迪暗示认可本片 引发广泛讨论
The implication of Kennedy's approval of this film are wide ranging.
原著小说由前共产党员撰写
The novel was written by a former communist.
剧本也由前共产党员改编
The screenplay was adapted by a former communist.
意味着黑名单的时代或许已经结束了
And this signifies the blacklist may be over,
寇克·道格拉斯和奥图·普莱明杰
as Kirk Douglas and Otto Preminger
公开宣称并挂名雇用黑名单上的编剧
have openly hired and credited blacklisted writers.
这明确批判了数十年来反共人士对艺术界的反对
This is a clear repudiation of a decade-long fight by anti-communists...
下一位得奖者
This next award is for the member
提升了电影的文学境界
who has advanced the literature of motion pictures.
有时候 我们中间有些人
Occasionally, there appears among us a person
洛杉矶 1970年3月
牺牲小我 照亮他人
who so subordinates his own ego to the concerns of others,
顺应社会一切准则
who lives in such harmony with all the standards of the community,
并受到众人的崇敬与爱戴
that he is revered and loved by everyone.
达尔顿·特朗勃 肯定不是这样的人
Such a man, Dalton Trumbo is not.
我很荣幸
It gives me great pleasure
将美国编剧公会终身成就奖
to present the Writers Guild of America Laurel Award
颁给达尔顿·特朗勃
to Dalton Trumbo.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢 非常感谢
Thank you, thank you very much.
感谢各位女士先生
Thank you, thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen.
通常我出席电影人聚会时
Often, when I stand before the film community,
房里都有一只看不见的大象
there's an elephant in the room.
那就是我
Me.
所以我想发表以下谈话
And I thought I would address that.
黑名单是邪恶时代的产物
The blacklist was a time of evil.
存活下来的人们
And no one who survived it
无一不曾被邪恶染指
came through untouched by evil.
当时的情况
Caught in a situation that had passed
非个人能够掌控
beyond the control of mere individuals.
而我们的行为反映了自己的天性
Each person reacted as his nature,
需求及信念
his needs, his convictions,
眼前形势强迫我们做了某些事
and his particular circumstances compelled him to.
那是个恐惧的年代
It was a time of fear.
无人可以幸免
And no one was exempt.
许多人丧失了家园
Scores of people lost their homes.
家庭分崩离析
Their families disintegrated. They lost!
有些人
And in some...
甚至葬送了生命
Some even lost their lives.
但当我们回顾那段黑暗时期
But when you look back upon that dark time,
我相信我们偶尔都会
as I think you should every now and then,
指认某人是英雄或恶人
it will do you no good
这于事无补
to search for heroes or villains.
我们之中没有善与恶
There weren't any.
只有受害者
There were only victims.
因为我们每一个人
Victims, because each of us
都是被强迫做出当时的言行
felt compelled to say or do things
否则我们不会那么做
that we otherwise would not.
我们伤害对方 或受到伤害
To deliver or receive wounds
但其实我们 并不想交换那些伤口
which we truly did not wish to exchange.
现在看着台下的家人们
I look out to my family sitting there,
我才明白 当时害他们受了多大的苦难
and I realize what I've put them through.
这对他们太不公平了
And it's unfair.
然而我太太却成功地 维系了家庭
My wife, who somehow kept it all together,
这令我惊奇不已
amazes me.
因此 我今晚说的这番话
And so what I say here tonight
并不想
is not intended
伤害任何人
to be hurtful to anyone.
而是试图治愈伤痛
It is intended to heal the hurt.
修补多年来
To repair the wounds which, for years,
不断被撕裂的伤口
have been inflicted upon each other.
最糟糕的是 这些伤口已刻在我们身上
And most egregiously, upon ourselves.
谢谢 由衷感谢大家
Thank you. Thank you kindly.
特朗勃终于在1975年
拿到因《勇敢的人》获得的奥斯卡奖
他于1976年过世 享年70岁
1993年 克莉欧代替特朗勃领取
因《罗马假日》获得的奥斯卡奖
克莉欧 于2009年过世 享年93岁
她一直没有再婚
好莱坞有数百人被列入黑名单
而全美则有数千人受到不白之冤
许多教师 军人 政府员工及家属
因此失业 破产 离婚 甚至自杀
非美活动调查委员会 持续调查国民
直到1975年为止
别走开 后面还有精采片段
若你能领取奥斯卡奖
If you receive the Oscar,
你打算做什么？
what do you intend to do with it?
我有个女儿 今年13岁
I have... I have a daughter, 13 years old.
我从她三岁起被列入黑名单
I've been blacklisted since she was three.
她知道
She's known the title
之后我写的每一部片子
of every motion picture I've written in this study.
而她一直保守这些秘密直到现在
And she's kept that title secret till now.
她是个战士
A soldier.
儿时当朋友问她
When her friends say to her, as children do,
"我爸是做这个的 你爸做什么？"
"My father does so-and-so. What does your father do?"
这对她而言是个头痛的问题
This has confronted her with a very real problem.
从她三岁起一直纠缠到现在
It confronts her with the problem,
and has since she was three,
她说不出自己的父亲是谁
of who her father really is.
以及他到底从事什么职业
And what her father really does.
我想
I, uh, think
如果我能拿到那座奥斯卡 我会送给她
I will give this Oscar, if I get it, to that girl.
我想我会告诉她
I think I will tell her,
现在 这个秘密
"Well, here is one secret
你不用再承担了
"you no longer need to be burdened with."
我会告诉她 我们的名字终于又能 重见天日
I'll tell her we have our names back again.